话说在前头 我们不是兄弟
Before you say anything, I'm not your brother.
－血缘只有一半 －搞什麽 干嘛一开口就这样？
-I'm your half-brother. -What was that?Why would you begin a conversation like that?
因为你打算跟我要钱
Because you are about to ask me for money,
我每次质疑为何要给你钱
and when I always say, "Why should I give you money?"
你就会回答 因为我俩是兄弟
you always say, "Because I am your brother,"
我之前都没声明 血缘只有一半
and I never point out you are my half-brother.
”玛莉” 反正最近有些状况‥
I never say it. But things happening around here lately...
帕斯顿 你还会乱想吗？
Hi, Paxton. How are your erratic head movements?
我看了文章才想问
I ask because I read an article.
好一点了
Yeah, they're under control.
水泥艺术品销路怎麽样？
How's the, uh, cement art work?
她刚卖了一个 拿到五万美元
She just sold a piece for $50,000.
主题是冻结的瀑布 很切合时事
A frozen waterfall.It felt appropriate for the times.
怎麽说切合？
How is it appropriate for the times?
－其实不重要 －我来电是想关心你们的近况
-You know what? It doesn't matter. -I was actually calling to see how you were.
听说纽约现在不太妙
'Cause I heard it's bad in New York.
是很糟 职篮比赛都取消了
It is bad. They canceled the NBA.
据说伦敦全面封城了
We heard London's under total lockdown.
说到这个 我正在放无薪假
I've been furloughed by the way.
－太棒了 －没错
- That's great! - Yeah.
我的人生已经彻底失去了意义
Now there is literally zero purpose to my life.
琳达怎麽样？
How is Linda?
总之在屋裡某个地方
Yeah, she's somewhere in the house.
你们闹僵了吗？
Is there some type of issue?
闹僵啊‥我想想
Is there an issue? Let me see.
瞎扯感情状况以免外界严密检视
Convenient lie to avoid forensic examination of our domestic
或者要照实说？ 还是瞎扯吧
circumstances or tell the truth?Okay, convenient lie.
我们没事 感情很好
No. There is no issue. We are fine.
－跟她说视讯上见 －大卫 我还卖了重机
-Can you tell her I'm gonna Skype her? -Also, David, I've sold my motorbike.
－什麽？ －已经成交了 对方会付钱
-You've what? -Yeah, I have a buyer. He'll pay me
只等心理炼狱的枷锁解开
when we are all unlocked from this fucking prison of psychological hell-chains.
我们捱过孤寂的火刑
Fucking flames of burning aloneness.
我已经隔离到分不清什麽是身体
The screw of isolation until you can't tell
什麽又是家具了
what is your body and what is furniture.
完全无法发动引擎 直接脱身
No possibility of revving the engine
你能感受到我的心情吗？
and riding away. Am I conveying anything of my mood to you?
你干嘛卖掉重机？
Why have you sold your bike?
你根本少不了它啊
You are your bike. Your bike is you.
没错 我把自己卖了
Yeah, I have sold myself.
抛售掉往日认同
I have sold my former self.
我觉得车子很可怜
I felt sorry for the bike.
应该有人珍惜这个自由的灵魂
It deserved someone who can do justice to its spirit.
突破重重制约
Someone who still breaks the fucking rules.
你跟琳达吵架了吗？
So, you and Linda, what, you had a fight?
琳达说本来打算跟我分手
Linda said she was planning to end our thing,
放下这段感情或诸如此类的关系
our relationship, our whatever this ever was,
因为我们渐行渐远
because we'd grown apart,
也就是她向上提升 我沉沦探底
meaning that she had gone up and I have gone down.
她原本打算在封城前走人
She was planning to end it before lockdown was announced.
我们互吼 口沫横飞
...droplets and moisture because we were shouting.
彼此都大放厥词
I said some things and she said some things
结果困在这儿 但话已出口
and now we are stuck here together with the things we said
就像锺声不断回荡
echoing around the house like fucking bells ringing.
我们被迫关在屋裡两周了
For two weeks we are locked together here.
老实说 我只是想听到人声
Anyway. Truth be told, I just wanted to hear someone's voice.
－结果你挑了我们吗？ －挺好的啊
- And you chose us? - Yeah, why not?
你的那个朋友麦克呢？
What happened to Mike? Your friend Mike.
不行 我跟麦克闹翻了
Oh, no, no. Mike and I are no longer speaking.
他踩了线‥外送来了
He crossed... My delivery!
麦克踩了大红线 他说肺炎病毒
Crossed an important threshold when, uh, when he said that
是犹太人秘密散布的外星基因体
the COVID virus was the consequence of the secret release by Jews of alien DNA
从中国高球场洒水器传播出来
into the water sprinkling system of a Chinese golf resort.
看来食物到了 我们先挂断吧
It looks like your food has arrived,so we'll let you go.
这不叫食物 只是个三明治
It's not food, it's a sandwich.
兄弟 撑著点
Yeah, hang in, brother.
－半个兄弟才对 －跟琳达说我会打过去
- Half-brother. - Tell Linda I'm gonna call her.
我会留纸条 搞得彼此更尴尬
Yeah, I'll leave her a note. Just to compound the oddness.
抗疫的代价一览无遗
The stark reality of fighting Coronavirus...
伦敦特拉法加广场原本人潮汹涌
...Trafalgar Square in London usually crowded.
社交疏离显然是进行式
Evidence of social distancing in action.
值此关键时刻
In this critically important time,
已确诊的鲍利强森首相公告‥
the Prime Minister Boris Johnson himself infected,but been sharing...
玛莉 你们那边好吗？
Maria, hey! Is everything okay?
都不赖 我们很健康
Oh, yeah, yeah. Everything's great.
刚才还跟帕斯顿通过电话
You know, we're staying strong. Yeah, we just talked to Paxton.
我拿枕头捂住还是隐约听到了
Hmm. Yes, I head. Some of it. I put a pillow over my head.
他说你有些症状
He said you had symptoms.
但愿已经没事了 难说
It passed I think. I hope. I don't know.
记得分享蔬果昔的食谱给我
Oh, green smoothie. You must send me that recipe.
不必食谱 做就对了
It's not a recipe, it's an action.
就扔点蔬果按钮绞成泥啊
You just put the green stuff in and press the on button.
你跟帕斯顿之间还好吧？
How are things with you and Paxton?
你明知一点也不好
You know everything is not okay.
不但一点也不好 还全都糟透了
Not only is everything not okay,nothing is okay.
每件事都烦 他的名字也一样
Everything is never okay. Even his name is not okay.
连他都说听到他的名字会倒楣
This is him speaking. He says even his name is a predictor of doom.
他最近就是这副德性
That's how he is lately.
他变了好多
He's changed so much.
人总是会变
Oh, we all change.
你和他都跟以前不一样了
I mean, Linda, you've evolved, he's mutated.
他需要人拉一把 我之前看到‥
He needs some help.I read an article..
你知道他之前说男人过了３５岁
Do you know he said the other day
还搭公车就是废物吗？
that any man over 35 who rides a bus is a failure?
他以前每天搭公车 说这种话只是在自虐
He rides the bus every day. Or he used to.He does it to torture himself.
男人的头脑都不好使
No man is ever really fully conscious, not really.
听说他卖了重机 可喜可贺
So, I heard he's selling his motorbike.That's a big step.
我俩都觉得他该放个假
Yeah, we both agreed that he needed some time,
所以他要卖车去哈萨克整顿自己
so he's planning on using the money from selling the bike to go to Kazakhstan to think about his life.
为什麽选哈萨克？
Why Kazakhstan?
我们十年前到那裡自驾旅游过
We went on a road trip there ten years ago.
十年前吗？ 久到算不清了
Ten years ago? A million years ago.
结果现在我俩都困在这裡
Anyway, now he is stuck here, and I am stuck here.
琳达 还有别人吗？
Linda, is there someone else?
没有 就我们两个
Nope, just me and him.
－我是说其他对象 －我没有
-No, I mean, like, another man. - No.
那女人呢？
A woman?
什麽？
What?
只是乱猜而已
I was just speculating.
记得我们在伦敦 越了线的那晚吧？
Thinking about that night we came to London and you and I went too far.
我们只是呼麻后起了玩心
Oh, that was just weed and curiosity.
琳达 我们都高潮了
We both had orgasms, Linda.
听说视讯通话其实有资安风险
You know they say these calls aren't really the most secure.
我有时会回忆那晚
I think about that night sometimes.
－是吗？ －对 你不会吗？
- You do? - Yeah, don't you?
玛莉 我整天都在跟人视讯通话
Mmm... Listen, Maria, I've been on Skype and Zoom calls all day.
因为公司不开门 我得好好休息
The office is locked down. I really gotta get some sleep.
－好 再见 －再聊
- Okay, bye. - Bye.
我爱你
I love you.
什麽？
What?
老天爷
God.
帕斯顿 你要出门吗？
Paxton, are you going somewhere?
－我能去哪裡？ －排气口为什麽接了管子？
-Where would I be going? -Why is the hose in your exhaust?
自拍一张而已
I was just gonna take a selfie.
有同事传讯问我怎麽熬过封城
Someone at work texted me and asked how I was coping with lockdown.
我要把废气接进安全帽自拍回覆
So I was gonna send a photo of myself with the hose shoved up my helmet by way of reply.
感觉很搞笑
I thought it'd be funny.
苦中作乐嘛
An amusing expression of despair.
你确定只是要自拍吗？
You were really just gonna take a selfie?
－我都拿了手机了 －不打算发动引擎吗？
-Yeah, I had the phone in my hand. -You weren't gonna start the engine?
但我哪裡也去不了啊
And go where? You can't go anywhere.
我一进来就闻到车库和摩托车味
I came in here and I could smell the garage and the bike.
那味道不知为何令人非常感伤
And the smell... it made me very sad for some reason.
柜子很油 你的屁股会沾得都是
That shelf's covered in oil, you're gonna get your ass covered in oil.
天啊 什麽日子嘛
Jesus, what a day!
不顺心吗？
Bad?
工作有些突发状况而已
No, just work. I had some bad news.
跟这一切比起来不算什麽
Nothing compared to... everything.
话说回来 我确实只打算自拍
I really was just gonna take a selfie, by the way.
话说回来 对了 不必担心‥
"By the way," "just so you know," "in case you were worried."
只是寻个开心罢了
Just... just a little game.
或者是预演
Or a rehearsal.
拜托你别认为我在图些什麽
I'm not... Please don't think I'm looking for anything.
你知道玛莉打来说她爱我吗？
You know Maria just called me and said that she loves me?
－什麽？ －我懂 到处有人跑来讲心底话
- What? - I know.Secrets coming out all over the place.
－你身上有家门钥匙吗？ －没有
-You got the key to get back in? - No.
那我就不锁门了
I'll leave the door open for you.
怎麽了？
What's wrong?
你拿排气管乱搞
You playing with the hoses and exhausts
我们却要装作没事
and we carry on as if everything was normal.
我最近是很不对劲
I'm not normal lately, I know that.
根本完全睡不著
I haven't been sleeping at all.
我一直有点怪
I've never been normal, but...
以前还引以为荣 但现在‥
I used to be quite proud of it. Now, I just...
－怎麽样？ －我彻底明白会搞得多麻烦了
- Just what? - I don't know.I'm just acutely aware of the inconvenience it causes.
我细密分析每一粒砂
My super analysis of every grain of sand.
每个词汇
Every word.
封城后变得更惨了
Being locked up is making it worse.
我们得想办法分开隔离
We have to find some way of getting through this separately.
现在只是恰巧困在同个屋簷下
We're only together because we're in the same house.
解封前就避开彼此‥怎麽了？
We can sort of move around each other until we're free...What? What is it?
没事
Oh, nothing.
晚安
Good night.
圣诞布置搞到现在还没收
It's a bit of Christmas decoration.It's been there since Christmas.
谘商师说学习容忍也算是测试
My therapist says I should try to tolerate it.To use it as a test.
我还捱得住就印证有进步了
Up until now, I've been able to live with it,as a test to prove my progress.
去他的进步 你拆掉就是了
Well, fuck progress.Why don't you take it down?
－可是谘商师说‥ －谘商师个鸟蛋 帕斯顿
- No, my therapist says... - Fuck the therapist. Paxton... - You almost did.
你就差点吃了
Grow up. Take it down.
别耍孩子气 看不顺眼就拆掉
If it bothers you, take it down, okay?
反正今年圣诞本来就不太愉快
Christmas is not exactly a great memory anyway, is it?
圣诞节确实闹得很不开心
Christmas is not a great memory. I agree with you.
我们从那时起就走不下去了吧？
Beginning of the end for us, don't you think?
我早在圣诞前就受够了
That was way before Christmas for me.
抱歉
Sorry.
怎麽会有人把诚实当上策？
Why do people think honesty is good?
你现在怎麽谘商？
What are you doing about therapy anyway?
我开视讯做谘商
I'm doing it on Zoom.
谘商师的家中牆上还挂了鹿角
My therapist has antlers on his wall.
帕斯顿 现在非比寻常
These are extraordinary circumstances, Paxton.
你本不该跟甩了你的女人同住 天花板上还留著金葱
You can't live with a woman who has dumped you and a piece of tinsel on the ceiling.
我们打算要一笑置之了吗？
Have we decided to laugh about all this?
有何不可 反正也没辄了
Why not?Nothing else we can do there, is there?
要椅子垫脚吗？
Do you want a chair?
好
Sure.
了不起
Bravo.
－该死 这样好多了 －等一下
- Fuck! That's better. - Hang on.
我在车库看到你时有个念头
You know, when I saw you in the garage I thought...
好几年前 跟你一起骑车的是我吗？
"Was it really me on the back of your bike all those years ago?"
是你没错
Yeah, it was you.
硬撑著大喊大叫
Hanging on and screaming.
我现在也硬撑著大喊大叫
Well, that's what I'm doing now.
但你或其他人都听不见
Hanging on and screaming, but you can't hear me.
算了 晚安
Nobody can. Anyway, good night.
大喊大叫什麽？
Screaming about what?
你有什麽好大喊大叫的？
What are you screaming about?
要叫的是我吧
I'm the one that's screaming!
抽烟可能致死 售价含税
陌生人
Hello, stranger!
你好
Hi.
你好吗？
How are you?
糟透了 你呢？
Terrible. You?
很惨
Awful.
大家好
Hello!
在这波特兰街监狱 有同胞想听我念诗吗？
Does anyone here in our lovely Portland Street prison want to hear a little poem?
我读了不少诗
I read a lot of poetry
最近失眠就又翻阅了不少
and I've read even more lately 'cause I can't sleep.How are you?
从此明白世上还有别人了无希望
that you're not the only human being on earth who's fucked up.
帕斯顿
Paxton!
你在搞什麽鬼？
What the fuck are you doing?
我在帮”狱友”解闷
I'm entertaining our fellow inmates.
这首诗提名”起身”
This poem is called Stand Up!
对了 作者是大卫劳伦斯
It's by D.H. Lawrence, by the way.
只是顺带一提 给想知道的人
"By the way," "just so you know," "in case you were worried."
好 我要朗诵了
All right, here goes.
”起身吧 但不为耶稣”
"Stand up, but not for Jesus!
”那为时已晚”
It's a little late for that.
”起身扞卫正义和幸福人生”
Stand up for justice and a jolly life.
”我会一起声援”
I'll hold your hat.
”小淘气们 起身扞卫正义”
Stand up, stand up for justice, ye swindled little blokes!
”起身奋力冲撞”
Stand up and do some punching,
”给他们颜色瞧瞧”
give 'em a few hard pokes.
”起身争取改变现状”
Stand up for a new arrangement for
”为所有人谋求机会”
a chance of life all round,
”力争自由和快乐”
for freedom and the fun of living,
”闯进去坚守阵地吧”
break in, and hold the ground!"
谢谢 吵醒各位真不好意思
Thank you.Sorry if I woke you.
但我最近精神状况不好
But I am going slightly mad lately.
在此给大家一个忠告
My advice to everyone
善用我们共同经历的奇幻时光
is to use these strange times we're all going through
把人生应得的事物抢回来
to steal all the things that you think life owes you.
回去睡觉 蠢材
Go to sleep, you bloody tosser!
－我睡得著就会去睡 －老兄 就让他念吧
-Yeah, well, if I could I would. -Hey, leave him be, mate!
之后翻到好诗再来跟各位分享
And if I come across any other good poems, I'll share it.
念得好
We love it!
－波特兰街的大家晚安 －晚安
-Good night, Portland Street. -Night, night!
感谢你
Thank you!
老天爷 求求你让我睡著
God, please let me sleep.
好多喔
不要啦
可能有人听见了
闭嘴 别把人引来
我对天发誓
I swear to God!
你们跑来我家院子做什麽？
What the fuck are you doing in my garden?
你还好吗？ 我们在采这东西
You all right?We're just gathering these.
只是罂粟的鳞茎而已
They're just poppies.They're bulbs of poppies.
我们社区的药头都被捕了
All the dealers in our estate have been arrested,
毕竟只有他们还上街活动
because they're the only people out on the streets, innit?
罂粟鳞茎是鸦片的原料
With these poppy bulbs, you can make a sort of opium.
划开表皮就能采收汁液
You just slit the skins and juice comes out.
－你们怎麽晓得这裡有？ －我们住在那边的大厦裡
-How did you know they were here? -We live in that tower block up there, bro.
朋友有望远镜 喜欢观星
Friend of ours has a telescope. He's into stars and shit.
我们用望远镜俯看房子找乐子
We've been looking down on houses for a laugh.
隔著窗户发现你家有罂粟
Looking through windows and then we saw all these growing in your garden.
我家庭院裡怎麽会长出罂粟？
What the fuck are they all doing growing in my garden?
７０年代有些嬉皮私占空屋
I think hippies used to squat in these houses in the '70s.
播种之后就任它们长了吧
I think they grew them and they just went wild.
－没错 －树汁要怎麽提炼？
-you 're right -How do you refine the juice?
不必提炼 滴在香烟上抽就好
You don't. You just drip it onto tobacco and then smoke it.
也可以混在可乐裡喝
Or you can mix it with Coca-Cola if you want and drink it.
我现在不抽烟或喝可乐了
Yeah, well, I don't smoke anymore or drink Coca-Cola,
也完全不嗑药
or do drugs of any kind,
但以前胡搞时会狂抽海洛因
but back in the bad old days I did smoke quite a lot of heroin.
这东西不像海洛因那麽猛
This is not as strong as heroin.
效果很温和
It's quite a gentle hit.
－算有机食材呢 没错 －有机啊？
- It's organic, bro. - Organic?
难怪那只刺蝟怪怪的
That would explain the hedgehog.
院子裡有只刺蝟超轻松随和
There's a hedgehog in this garden who is unusually friendly and relaxed.
你们觉得抽一点点能助眠吗？
Would a very small amount help you sleep, do you think?
睡得可香了 一夜到天明
You sleep like a baby. Smooths everything out.
什麽烦人想法都会不见
No mean voices in the night.
放下烦人事该有多好
No mean voices in the night.That would be nice.
这样啊‥
Well, well, well.
帕斯顿
Paxton!
帕斯顿 天杀的
Paxton, for fuck's sake!
托比
Hey, Toby!
你还会咳嗽吗？
Hey, how's the cough?
好一点了 你呢？
A bit better I think. How are you?
我应该中了 希望已经康复
I had it I think, but it's passed.
病毒就像女武神
I hope. It's like a Valkyrie.
什麽？
What?
维京传说中有种神祇 会在战前定人生死
It's a Viking spirit who, before battles, decides who will live and who will die.
女武神的决定毫无理由
Valkyries, uh, make their choices with no reason.
不讲道德 无关善恶
No morality, no good or bad.
大家得病与否简直莫名其妙
It's just so unfair how some people get so sick and some don't.
托比 你来了 最近怎麽样？
Toby, you're back. How are you?
”唐诺” 棒得很 谢谢
Gangster. Thank you.
大家好
Hello!
唐诺
Donald!
－你打了领带 －这条是我爸的旧领带
-You got a tie on. -One of my father's old ones.
我正缅怀老式礼节呢
I've become nostalgic for old-fashioned formality.
我在视讯时会想像男人都勃起了
On these Zoom things, I always imagine every man has an erection.
－唐诺 你在家裡吗？ －这是我妈的家
-Donald, is that your house? -Uh, no. I'm at my mother's.
安东尼把我赶出门了
Anthony threw me out.
这样违法吧？
Oh! That's not allowed, is it?
我们在某晚大吵 摊了牌
We had an awful night, and everything came out.
原来我们痛恨彼此
We found out we, uh, hate each other. So...
大家好
Hi!
梅莉莎 意大利还好吗？
Uh, Melissa. Hey, how is Italy?
听说很惨
I hear it's bad there.
不对 我正在瑞典
No, I'm in Sweden.
－什麽‥？ －你自己看
- What? - Look.
这裡的酒吧还开著门
You can go to bars here.
有人坏坏吗？
Hmm. Is anybody obeying the rules?
都十年不嗑药了 我可真聪明
After ten years sober, that was fucking smart.
我们还在等谁？
Wait, who are we waiting for?
应该是提莫西吧
Timothy, I think.
提莫西没事吧？
Oh, is Timothy okay?
－为什麽会有事？ －他有慢性病
-Why wouldn't he be? -Well, he's got an underlying health condition.
你知道是哪种病吗？
Do you know which one?
不晓得 他感觉就像 有慢性病的人
No.He just seemed like a sort of person who would have an underlying health condition.
我们能先不管提莫西吗？
Shall we just start without Timothy?
对了 我还穿了皮鞋
By the way, I am also wearing shoes.
我们该开始了 我有要事得宣布
Seriously, we should start.I have something to say. Something important.
等等 提莫西传讯息来
Oh, um, hang on. Oh, it's a message from Timothy.
天啊
God!
他中标了吗？
Has he got it?
”亲爱的琳达 从今早九点开始”
"Dear, Linda. As of 9:00 a.m. this morning,
”我于米拉克媒体公司 所提之离职申请即刻生效”
I am resigning my position at Miracore Media
”我花了点时间独自思考”
with immediate effect. I have had time alone to think
”我发现公司只会制造 自肥的媒体新闻”
and I've realized that what this company does is just self-indulgent media bullshit,
”支持著侵蚀全世界的 国际资本主义”
supporting corrosive international capitalism around the world.
”我们应该发挥创意拯救地球”
We should be using our creativity to save the planet,
”而非向法西斯独裁者的老婆 贩售手提包”
not sell handbags to the wives of fascist dictators.
”隔离中的提莫西敬上”
Yours in isolation. Timothy."
想来是都在看 大卫艾登堡的纪录片
Just been watching David Attenborough documentaries, I imagine.
－他是崩溃了吗？ －好 不必等提莫西了
-Did he snap? -Okay, so there's no need to wait for Timothy.
赶快把会开完
Let's get this done.
听起来事态严重 琳达
Sounds awfully grave, Linda.
－爹地‥ －爸爸在开视讯会议 等等
- Daddy, Daddy. - Shh. Daddy's on a call.
昨天我与芝加哥总部开了场 很长的视讯会议
Yesterday, I had a very long Zoom call with head office in Chicago.
各大洲的代表都与会了
All continents were represented.
在这流年不利中 全球分公司都面临一样的问题
And it seems that all over the world the company is facing the same at this difficult time.
身为米拉克媒体 英国分公司的执行长
As CEO of Miracore UK, it is
我‥
my...
非常遗憾地通知各位
unfortunate duty to let you know
我们将针对部分董事会成员 实施无薪假
that there will be some furloughing of employees across the board.
并从今天起执行强制性裁员
And also a number of compulsory redundancies effective from today.
我想前浪势必要死在沙滩上了
I assume the Inuit system of leaving the old on the ice will be in play.
唐诺 不要贸然下定论
Donald, please don't jump to conclusions.
琳达 这话是什麽意思？
Linda, what do you mean?
正常来说我会召集大家来开会
Uh, in normal times, I would've gathered everyone into a room...
大家？
Everyone?
会召集诸位来开这场视讯会议
Everyone on this Zoom call is on this call
是因为各位的职位已无发展潜能
because all of your positions have been deemed no longer sustainable,
你们在米拉克媒体公司的 劳动契约将即刻终止
and as of today your contracts of employment with Miracore will be terminated.
好 真高兴我在家
Okay.I'm glad I'm home.
我去喂鸡了
I'm going to feed the fucking chickens.
梅莉莎
这样真的很过分 琳达 你良心不会痛吗？
This is really bad, Linda. How do you sleep?
娜塔莎
你好
Hello!
Hello.
你看我的恐龙
Look at my dinosaur.
爹地‥
Daddy...
马侃‥我以为强制休假
Malcolm, I thought being furloughed
是指政府付薪水 我们不用做事
meant that the government pays your wages,but you don't do any work.
的确‥但疫情之下情况都变了
Yeah, it does, it does, it does.But COVID makes everything different.
很悲哀‥
So sad. So sad.
我教牧关怀的对象都深受影响
All of this is impacting on everyone in my pastoral care.
对 但我不是你教牧关怀的对象
Yeah, but I'm not in your pastoral care, right?
我是你的员工
I work for you.
我只想知道既然放了无薪假
And all I wanna know is,
你为何又叫我工作？ 这样不是违法吗？
if I am furloughed, why are you asking me to work?
我是基督徒
It's illegal, isn't it?
大家都知道你是基督徒
I'm a Christian man.We all know that you are a Christian man.
你说得像我在逼你信教
You say it like I ram it down your throats.
我没有逼你信教
I do not ram it down your fucking throat.
马侃 你就直说要我做什麽吧
Malcolm, just tell me, what is it that you want me to do?
现在出状况了 帕斯顿
We have a situation, Paxton.
你再不明说 我就要挂电话了
Yeah, I'm leaving this call unless you tell me.
我还听完你的祷告了
I sat through your prayer.
每次视讯我都会以祷告开场
I begin every FaceTime with a prayer.
这是我的个人选择吧 我是老板嘛
My choice. Right? I'm the boss.
对啊 你是老板 所以老板你到底要我做什麽？
Yeah, you are the boss. So what do you want me to do, boss?
由于封城 西区的各大百货都要关门了
Due to lockdown, all the major department stores in the West End are closing.
许多货运公司‥ 包括公对公专业货运公司
B2B Pro Freight Services are among several freight companies
要将西区畅货中心 价值不斐的零售物件
which have been asked to transport valuable retail items from the West End outlets
转移到达根罕这种鸟地方的 保安储藏中心
to secure storage facilities in shitholes like Dagenham.
帕斯顿 你也看到了 我们的社会结构已然崩毁
The fabric, Paxton, of our society is torn, you see that.
对骚乱暴动与趁火打劫的恐惧
Fears of rioting and looting.
瘟疫
Pestilence.
世界末日般的宣言
Apocalyptic words.
我给你十秒讲清楚到底要我干嘛
I'm giving you ten seconds to tell me what it is you want me to do.
－十 九 八‥ －我们需要像你这样的司机
- Ten, nine, eight... - Because of this crisis, we urgently need drivers.Drivers like you.
－七 六 五 四‥ －百货只核准一种载货司机
- ...seven, six, five... -Department stores only allow their goods to be transported by drivers
－三 二‥ －没有前科的司机
- who do not have criminal records. - ...three, two...
我再说一次
I repeat.
公对公专业货运公司急需 名下登记没有前科的司机
B2B Pro Freight Services have urgent need for drivers registered to us who do not have criminal records.
那你找我干嘛？
So why are you talking to me?
伦敦有十六家百货 需要我运送高价物件
I have contracts to carry valuables from 16 department stores
他们要在四天内清空
across London, and they all want everything out in the next four days.
我只有两个司机
And I only have two fucking drivers.
所以你有什麽办法？
So what's your solution?
欺骗 原谅 救赎 阿堵物
Deception. Forgiveness. Redemption. Bunce.
阿堵物是怎样？
What the fuck is bunce?
以前人常说的钱
Old East End word for cash, Paxton,
这是用漫天谎言 换取的不义之财
in return for grand deception.
是我的宽宏大量 与你的救赎之路促成的
Facilitated by my forgiveness and your redemption.
好 讲重点‥马侃
All right, get there. Get there, Malcolm.
我弄了个身份安全值Ａ２的证件
I've printed off an ID with a security level A2.
没有前科 上面有你的照片跟名字
Clean. With your photo on it and a name.
不是你的名字
It is not your name.
我无法正式终结你的无薪假 把工作派给你
I can't officially take you off furlough and give you this work,
因为你以前老是飙车搞事
because you used to be a bike slag,
我只能让你假装成别人 再用现金付薪水给你
so I will have to pretend you are someone else and pay you in cash.
你在公司当了七年的司机
You've worked for this company as a driver for seven years.
我从未听过任何客户抱怨过你
And I have never had a single complaint.
当然你都送低单价的物件
You've only ever driven low value packages,
但我相信你是个值得信任的人
but I believe you are a man who can be trusted.
我是
That I am.
我确实值得人信任
Yeah, I can be trusted.
那件事都多久以前了
I mean, what happened was a long time ago.
我不想知道
Yeah, I don't wanna to know.
那只是飞车党车手间的冲突
No, it was biker versus biker.
上帝会宽恕你 公司也会宽恕你
The Lord forgives. B2B Pro Freight Services forgives.
要不是因为那晚的事被起诉
If it wasn't for the fucking convictions from that night,
我的人生会完全不一样
my whole life would've been radically different.
日薪两百英镑现金
Two hundred a day in cash.
我不在乎现金 我要跟你谈条件 马侃
I don't care about the cash. I wanna make a deal with you, Malcolm.
我只有一个条件
Look, I will do this on the condition
搞定这件事后 你会考虑升我做行政文书
that when this is all over, you will consider me for a clerical position.
就因为一晚的错误 我的人生就毁了
My entire life has been fucked up because of things I did on one night.
我老婆‥已经放弃我了
My wife...My wife has grown out of me,
因为我还是那个 只会开卡车的烂货
because I am still Mr. Fuck-All behind the wheel of a van.
我不是笨蛋
I am not stupid.
我会读诗
I read poetry.
－我能成材 －我有通电话要接 帕斯顿
-I could be someone. -I've got another call, Paxton.
现在很忙 西区要忙疯了 你到底接不接？
It is a very busy time, the West End is going mad.Will you do it?
好 我要是接了这活儿 你要说到做到
All right, if I do this for you, Malcolm,I want you to practice what you preach.
关于原谅 迷途羔羊 还有救赎那些的
About forgiveness, and lost sheep and redemption,
给我一个回头是岸的机会
all of it, and give me a chance to come off the road.
凡事都有可能 帕斯顿 上帝保佑你
Everything is possible, Paxton.God bless you.
周四去塞尔福裡百货 周五去夏菲尼高百货
Selfridges, Thursday. Harvey Nichols, Friday.
－周六是哈洛德百货 －好
-Harrods on Saturday. - Right, yeah.
我把详细班表跟新的证件寄给你
I will e-mail your full itinerary and your new identity.
好‥周六送完哈洛德百货后‥
Okay, okay. And after... After Harrods on Saturday...
上帝保佑你 帕斯顿
God bless you, Paxton.
吸烟可导致肺癌
可恶
Shit.
盖伊
琳达 封城还好吗？
Hey, Linda, how's lockdown?
颇惨的
It's pretty bad.
芝加哥怎麽样了？
How's Chicago?
我在弗蒙特
I'm in Vermont.
全家搬到弗蒙特
Yeah, moved the family out to Vermont.
大家在这裡都超开心的
We're all here crazy happy.
小孩很吵 所以我买了新耳机
Kids make a lot of noise, so I got these new AirPods Pro.
有降噪功能 真的很棒 我什麽都听不到
Noise canceling. They work, like, you literally can't hear anything.
我没有那种耳机
No, I don't have those.
我从你的表情就知道
I can see in your face
你已经跟壹凡资的人们谈过了
that you, uh, spoke to the guys at Events
也跟他们更新了状况
and delivered the update.
更新 对 我跟他们更新状况
Update. Yeah. Yeah, I updated them.
你有没有读我的讯息给他们听？
Did you read them my message?
”公司是大家庭”那封吗？
The stuff about the Miracore family?
没有‥我觉得词不达意‥
No, no, no, I didn't think that would translate. Um...
琳达 我是发自内心写这封讯息
Linda, I wrote that message from the heart.
我是真心的
I really meant what I said.
我真不敢相信你没念出来
I can't believe you didn't read it out to them.
我觉得很不妥 说什麽”米拉克是个大家庭”
I didn't think it was appropriate to say that "Miracore is a family
”家庭终究会走到这一天”
and there comes a time in every family's life
”有些成员得飞出鸟巢 才能维系美好家庭”
when it's best if some family members fly the nest."
哪裡不妥？
Why is that not appropriate?
因为他们不是飞出鸟巢吧
Because they're not flying the nest, are they?
他们是被扔出鸟巢 砸到树下的杂草中
They're being thrown out of the nest into the long grass under the tree.
没有树啊 哪裡来的树？
There's no tree. What tree?
是你说鸟巢的 盖伊 有鸟巢的比喻就要有一棵树
It's your nest, Guy. You came up with the analogy of the nest.So there has to be a tree.
你是不是脑子烧坏了 琳达？
Do you have a temperature, Linda?
封城之前 本来安排了两场大型活动
Um, there are two big events which were already set up when lockdown began.
一场在西田百货
One was at Westfield,
另一场是伊芙许沃 在哈洛德百货借点举办的活动
the other one was the Eve Schwarz store takeover at Harrods.
但西田跟哈洛德都关门了
But both Westfield and Harrods have closed their door.
我好爱哈洛德
I love Harrods.
我也是 我在哈洛德工作过五年
Yeah, I love Harrods, too.
那是我人生中最快乐的时光
I worked there for five years, they were the happiest of my life.
总之伊芙许沃 这次的系列规模盛大
Anyway, the launch of Eve Schwarz collection was going to be huge,
所以基于场地大小与保安 我选了哈洛德百货
so I chose Harrods because of its size and level of security.
你选的？ 我以为梅莉莎才是活动策略长
You chose? I thought Melissa was head of events strategy.
有时我会质疑她的‥不重要
Yeah. Sometimes I questioned her... It doesn't matter.
你帮著这部门太久了
You've been carrying that department a long time.
是啊 毕竟是大家庭嘛 家人不就是要这样吗？
Yeah, well, they were family, weren't they?And that's what you do with family.
你会一直帮助他们 直到收到芝加哥总部的裁员指示
You carry them until you get a direction from Chicago to drop them,
然后按令行事开除他们
and then you dutifully drop them.
总之我们在哈洛德放了 市价五百万的珠宝 服装与首饰
Anyway, at Harrods, we have five million dollars worth of jewelry,
都是为了品牌走秀 与借点办展安置的
clothing and accessories already installed for the catwalk
都属于米拉克的保管责任范围
and store takeover under Miracore liability.
其中包括哈裡斯鑽石
And that includes the Harris Diamond
本来是要当走秀的重头戏
which was to be the centerpiece of the show.
哈裡斯鑽石 属于我们的保险责任？
The Harris Diamond is under our insurance liability?
是‥
It's, um...
鑽石目前安置在哈洛德的 安全金库中 没错
It's safe in the Harrods' secure vault, but, yes.
弗蒙特去死
我已经向品牌提议
I suggested to the people at Eve Schwarz
尽快将物件移至 哈洛德的保安仓库中直到‥
that we put everything into Harrods' secure storage as quickly as possible until this, um...
直到封城落幕
Uh, until this situation is ended.
但保险又有个问题 就是‥
But we have a problem with insurance. You see...
伊芙许沃的保单上指出 品牌商品不得进行存放
So, Eve Schwarz's insurance policy means that they are not allowed to store their merchandise
除非在品牌自己的监管之下
except under their own corporate supervision.
因此要透过安全的移转方式 将商品送出百货
So the merchandise will have to be taken out of the store in secure transportation.
弗蒙特好烂
总之 百货都在安排物件配送
Anyway, the stores are allocating for collection.
西田是周五 哈洛德是周六
We have Westfield on Friday, Harrods on Saturday.
接著我们要讨论 你的职位与薪资
And then we discuss your role and your salary.
接下来会有许多新的职务
There'll be a lot of new responsibilities.
公司有重大改变
Things are changing.
真是好消息 谢谢
That's excellent news. Thank you.
帮我跟伦敦打声招呼
Say hello to London.
－好好享受弗蒙特 －当然
- Enjoy Vermont. - You bet.
弗蒙特去死 弗蒙特好烂
可恶 搞什麽 该死 昆恩
What? Oh, fuck! Quinn!
我要去阴尸路超市买牛奶 我们还需要什麽吗？
I'm going to the land of the Walking Dead to buy some milk.Do we need anything else?
我说”我们” 不是要暗示我们是同心同体
I say the word "we" without any attempt to suggest a unified entity,
但我们分两趟各买各的东西 实在很没意义
but there's no point in us both going separately to get our own provisions.
外面越来越危险了
It's getting rough out there.
而且我越发觉得 像我这种真的坐过牢的人
And increasingly, I think people like me who have spent time in real prison
在这种新生活中如鱼得水
are thriving in this new reality.
真的是‥帕斯顿 算了 进来吧
Oh, you know what, Paxton, fuck it. Come in.
好的 帕斯顿 是这样的 除了牛奶
All right, Paxton, here it is. In addition to milk,
我还需要香烟
I need cigarettes.
－什麽？ －我本来想掩饰自己烟瘾复发
- What? - I was trying to hide that I'm smoking again,
但反正我们已经分开了 这件事也不重要了
but since we're no longer together, it doesn't really matter, does it?
你又抽烟了？
You are smoking?
没错 我打算抽到封城结束
Yes. I plan to carry on just until this thing is over.
其实这感觉棒透了
It's magnificent, actually.
你什麽时候又开始抽烟的？
And when did you start smoking again?
圣诞节前
Just before Christmas.
为何？
Why?
我去巴黎时开始的
I started smoking again when I went to Paris.
－你去巴黎？ －对 我去了巴黎没跟你说
- You went to Paris? - Yes, I went to Paris.I didn't tell you I went to Paris.
麦克埃辛邀我去巴黎 我就去了
Michael Essien invited me to Paris and I went.
我的谘商师说 这样叫自白滚雪球
Okay, my therapist identifies these moments as confession avalanche.
麦克埃辛是哪位？
Who the fuck is Michael Essien?
他是米拉克媒体公司的创办人 德国富人排名第七
He is the founder of Miracore,seventh wealthiest man in Germany.
－你跟他去巴黎？ －不算
- And you went to Paris with him? - Not quite.
他邀请六个国家的执行长 去巴黎庆祝他的六十大寿
He invited the CEOs from six countries to come to Paris for his 60th birthday celebration.
你介意我点烟吗？ 我已经熄了两次‥
Do you mind if I light this thing? I've put it out twi...
不对啊 这是我的个人选择 我何必问你
And, you know what? Actually, it's my choice. Why am I even asking?
我到饭店的宴会厅时 认识了六个跟我一样的执行长
When I got to the hotel, there was this banqueting suite and I met six other CEOs just like me,
但当时我刚上任
only I had just become a CEO,
我还没意识到自己的身份 直到我看到其他执行长
so I didn't realize exactly who I was until I saw the other CEOs,
我这才确认了现在的身份
and then I was like, "Oh, so that's who I am now."
我们坐在桌旁喝香槟
And we sat around this table, drinking champagne,
对话中充斥著小人物的附和
and the conversation was lots of little voices saying "yes,"
与一声大人物的赞同 那是麦克埃辛的声音
and one big voice saying "good," Michael Essien's voice.
大人物接著说了”新兴市场” 然后我‥
And then the big voice said, "Emerging markets" and I...
你懂那种别人说得很抽象 但你却有个具体画面的感觉吗？
You know how sometimes when people say something abstract, I actually see it?
我们以前的确抽了很多大麻
Well, we did smoke a lot of weed in the bad old days.
当他说”新兴市场”时 我眼前浮现了这个‥东西
When he said "Emerging markets," I saw this...
这个形体从桌底冒出来 在我们的脚边游走
thing, this shape appearing from under the table and swimming around our legs.
我那晚好像真的发烧了
I think I actually did have a temperature that night. But, anyway,
然后他说了”香烟与药品”
then he said "Cigarettes and pharmaceuticals,"
我喝了点香槟时 又有人说”协调人”
and I drank some champagne and someone said "facilitators,"
那些人负责说服政府 商品的安全无虞
that is people who persuade governments that products are safe and okay.
大人物接著说协调人 是整间连锁的链接关键
And the big voice said that facilitators were now a huge link in the chain
我就看见了爬满海藻的大铁链
and I saw this big chain dripping seaweed
接著大人物举杯向贪腐致敬
and then the big voice raised a toast to corruption,
大家都嘲讽地笑了 包括我
and everybody laughed ironically, including me.
帕斯顿 看著我
Paxton, look at me!
然后这东西 这形体 在我脚边游走
And this thing, this shape, it was swimming around my fucking legs
大人物接著说新兴市场 是米拉克的一大收益
and then the big voice said, emerging market were now some big percentage of Miracore's profits,
因此欧洲分公司要进行 合理化的改革
and so there would have to be rationalization in Europe.
我有点想吐所以喝了点水 但又觉得快晕倒
And I drank some water, because I felt a little sick,
可是服务生问要不要白兰地 我就说好
but also like I might pass out, but then the waiter said "brandy," so I said yes.
所以呢‥
And, so,
就在圣诞节前的巴黎餐桌上 敲定了合理化的改革
the rationalization was planned right there at that table in Paris before Christmas.
而我早上开除的那些好人
And the nice people that I fired earlier today,
他们才不是像我说那样 因为疫情才被开除
they weren't fired because of a virus, like I told them,
那都是假的
that was a lie.
他们都是因为这鬼东西 才被开除的
They were fired because of this...this thing, this shape,
这东西随著我回到房间
that swam with me all the way back to my room,
为了摆脱它 我还拿了个丑陋的玻璃天鹅
and to get rid of it, I used the disgusting glass swan
朝著全身镜砸下去
to smash a full length mirror,
但我可没打算整晚踩著碎玻璃
and rather then walk across broken glass all night,
所以我决定搭最后一班 往伦敦的火车回家
I decided to take the last train home to London,
我抵达巴黎北站时 一名游民女子向前跟我要烟抽
and when I got to the Gare du Nord station,a homeless woman cameand asked me for a cigarette.
我说我不抽烟 但还是帮她买了一包
I told her that I didn't smoke, but I decided to buy her a pack anyway,
想说也许小小的善举 会让沦落至斯的我觉得好一点
because I thought that maybe kindness might make me feel better about what
看她点烟时 我也决定来一根
I had become. And when she lit her cigarette,I decided to have a cigarette, too.
当我把烟吸进去时
And when I drew in the smoke,
那东西就不动了
the thing stopped swimming.
然后我坐在长椅上等火车
So I sat down on the bench and I waited for my train.
那就是我烟瘾复发的原因
And that is why I started to smoke again.
但回到你刚刚的问题
But... to complete the answer to your original question,
除了牛奶与香烟
in addition to milk and cigarettes,
我们还需要面包
we need bread
还有葡萄酒
and fucking wine.
天啊
God!
怎样？
God what?
你听起来真的发烧了
Well, it sounds like you did have a temperature.
听说圣诞节前就有疫情了
You know, they say this thing was around before Christmas.
帕斯顿 才不是 跟病毒完全无关
Paxton, no! It's not about the virus.
而是我终于意识到自己的本质 与我的工作为何
It's about me realizing who I am and what I do for a living.
虽然重新审视人生 似乎是新冠疫情的副作用
Although a complete re-examination of one's life does seem to be a COVID side effect.
－你砸烂镜子？ －对‥因为我看到自己的倒影
- You smashed a mirror? - Yeah.Yeah, because I was in it.
我还砸了香槟酒瓶跟酒杯
I also smashed a champagne bottle,
本来还要再砸个 玻璃马匹与骑士
some champagne glasses, and I was about to smash a glass horse and jockey,
但我决定要留著
but then I decided to keep it,
结果却被我忘在火车上
but then I left it on the fucking train.
我就是像你以前说的那样 ”暴怒维京人”
Basically, I went, what you used to call, "Full Viking."
其实我看到碎裂的镜子中 自己愤怒的倒影时想到了你
In fact, when I broke the mirror and I saw my furious face in the cracked glass,
真贴心 感恩
That's very sweet. Thank you.
你为何不跟我说？
Why didn't you tell me?
那时是初冬 我们的感情寒冬
It was the onset of winter. Our winter.
反正我也没跟任何人说
And anyway, I didn't tell anybody,
因为只要不说出去 这件事就能当没发生过
because if you don't tell anybody, then it didn't happen.
－收到镜子的赔偿单了吗？ －帕斯顿‥
- Did you get a bill for the mirror? - Paxton...
帕斯顿 管那面镜子去死 跟镜子完全无关‥
Paxton, fuck the mirror. It's not about the mirror, it's about...
以前要是发生这种事
Previously, at this point,
－我会抱抱你 －不用 没必要
- I would've hugged you. - No, really, there's no need.
而且你也要去采买了
And anyway, besides, you're going shopping.
牛奶 面包 葡萄酒 香烟
So, uh, milk, bread, wine, cigarettes.
可能还要买鸡蛋
And probably eggs.
那我还要买小麦面粉 我要做面包
I'm gonna put white flour on the list.I'm gonna make bread.
－拜托不要 －我说‥
- Please don't. - You know...
你刚刚那段不是什麽自白
what you just said wasn't a confession.
我又没说是自白
I didn't say it was a confession.
－因为你没做错事 －不是 那段只是在解释
-'Cause you didn't do anything wrong. -No, it was an explanation.
你做的每件事都是对的
You did everything right.
你想听听什麽叫自白吗？
You wanna hear a confession?
我早上睡过头是因为昨晚‥
This morning I overslept, because last night
我嗑了鸦片
I took opium.
真的
Yes!
是真的 比你抽烟严重多了
Yes.Much worse than your cigarettes.
我在花园裡的绿色花苞上 舔了点鸦片吃
I licked opium off little green bulbs from the garden.
真的 花园裡海洛因比比皆是
Yes, I did.Our garden is full of heroin.
晒衣绳再过去一点 就是罂粟花之乡
You go beyond the washing line, it's like the Helmand Province.
－你都戒十年了 帕斯顿 －抽烟也没好到哪裡去
-After ten years, Paxton? -Smoking isn't so great either.
我最近有点挫折
You know, I've had some setbacks lately.
我告诉你 帕斯顿
Yeah, well, you know what, Paxton?
从巴黎回来后 我每早喝的蔬菜果昔
You know that green smoothie that I have in the mornings since Paris,
裡面可掺了两小杯伏特加 只有两杯喔
there's two shots of vodka in it.
－你骗人 －并没有
- Just two but... - You are lying.
不是每天都有 但有时候会加
No, I'm not.Not every morning, but some mornings I do it. I have done it.
你以为我是因为不断升官 才这麽开心又正常
You think I'm so happy and normal is 'cause I keep getting promoted.
人们真的脑袋不清楚
People get confused.
没有 我从不会说你快乐又正常
No, I've never accused you of being happy and normal, Linda.
因为我就不是
'Cause I'm not!
懂吗 我看得见抽象概念 真应该去当个艺术家
All right? I see concepts.I should've been an artist.
以装没事假幸福的女性角度来看 你感到不快乐
You are unhappy in an outwardly "happy,let's pretend it's all fine" female way,
而我的不快乐是以挫败‥
and I am unhappy in an obviously thwarted,
－失败又没雄风的男性角度来看 －不行‥我不能再跟你吵这个
- unfulfilled, castrated male way. - I can't. I can't.Do not go down this road again, okay?
你就采买吧 牛奶 面包
Just go to the store. Milk, bread,
葡萄酒 香烟 鸡蛋
wine, cigarettes, eggs.
好 管你的 我偏要买面粉
Yeah, and fuck you, I'm buying flour.
随便
Fine!
等等 你有口罩吗？
Wait. Do you have a mask?
没有 我没口罩
No, I don't have a mask, no.
那你应该找个东西遮住口鼻
Well, you'll have to tie something around your mouth and nose.
要命
Fuck!
是我的旧头巾
My old bandana.
对啊
Hmm. Yeah,
现在戴这个不是抗争 而是服从政府了
well, it's no longer a symbol of rebellion.It's now government advice.
在南达科他州斯特吉斯 初见时你就戴那样
You were wearing that when I met you in Sturgis, South Dakota.
看起来像个亡命之徒
I thought you looked like a desperado.
我只是想挡沙尘
No, I was just trying to get the dust out of my mouth.
别毁了我的回忆
Don't spoil it.
记得买牛奶和鸡蛋 亡命之徒
Don't forget the milk and the eggs, Desperado.
待在家裡
往前移动
Oi! Move forward.
快往前
Go ahead then.
少烦我
Fuck off.
－你有几个屁股？ －少烦我
-Oi. How many asses have you got? -Fuck off!
不放纵毋宁死
帕斯顿
Paxton.
大声说出巴黎那件事后 我思考过了
Hearing the story about Paris out loud, it made me think...
封城结束后 我可能会离开米拉克
When lockdown's over, I'm going to think about leaving Miracore.
这干我什麽事？
Why are you telling me?
马侃 拨号中
－你找我？ －我们的天父 我祈求你
-You called? -Oh, Lord who art in heaven, I beseech you,
垂怜我与帕斯顿 宽恕我们的欺瞒之罪
look favorably upon Paxton and myself and forgive us the sin of deception
饶恕寻求救赎途中 必犯之过 阿门
which we are jointly about to commit in pursuit of his ultimate redemption. Amen.
－阿门 －这段祷文是为你量身打造的
-Amen. -Every prayer is tailored to suit the person I am calling.
不是我就是耶稣写的
Either it's me writing the words or it's Jesus.
有什麽事吗 马侃？
What do you want, Malcolm?
我弄到你的假识别证了 薇吉妮亚会送去给你
I've got your fake ID sorted.Virginia is delivering the ID card.
我只是想确定你会加入
I wanted to make sure you'd be in.
－大家都加入了 马侃 －新名字传给你了
-You know what, Malcolm? Everybody's in. -And I've sent you your new name.
用简讯传的 在你手机裡
I texted it to you. It's on your phone.
好的
Okay.
用这个新名字开启全新人生
A new name for the beginning of a new life.
我的新名字是‥
And my new name is...
－埃德加爱伦坡？ －没错
-Edgar Allen Poe. -Yeah.
这个‥
Yeah, uh...
马侃 这个名字很显然不能用
Yeah. Malcolm, I obviously can't use this name.
为什麽不能？
Why not?
我希望这是玩笑 但我知道你不来这套
I'm hoping this is a joke,but I know you, so it's probably not.
什麽玩笑？
What joke?
好吧 埃德加爱伦坡 是一个知名的‥
Okay.Edgar Allan Poe is the name of a famous,
一个大红大紫的 美国小说家兼诗人
like a...like a very famous American novelist and poet.
从没听过他
Never heard of him.
我跟你打包票
Well, I assure you,
埃德加爱伦坡 是一个大红大紫的‥
Edgar Allan Poe is actually a very famous
我很喜欢的美国作家
American writer who I'm actually very fond of.
埃德加是我想的 是我祖父的名字
It was me that came up with Edgar.It's my grandad's name.
－那爱伦坡又是谁想的？ －派遣部的马丁
-So who came up with the "Allen Poe" part? -Martin in dispatch.
该死
Fuck.
派遣部的马丁讨厌我
Martin in dispatch hates me.
他故意要让我别扭 害我不好过
He's deliberately suggested this to make my life strange and unbearable.
但识别证已经做好了
Well, the card's already been laminated.
马侃 我不能这样 走进西区的高级百货
Malcolm, I can't go into expensive department stores
还期望他们信任我
in the West End, right,and expect them to entrust me
让我保护高价衣服和珠宝
with valuable clothing and jewelry,
我的名字是该死的埃德加爱伦坡
and tell them that my name is Edgar Allen fucking Poe!
他若那麽有名 我怎麽没听过？
If he's so famous, how come I've never heard of him?
－因为你不看书 －我会看《圣经》
-'Cause you don't read books! -I read the Good Book.
他是美国人 当然不在圣经裡
But he's not in the Bible, obviously. He's an American.
有人听过 叫埃德加爱伦坡的作家吗？
Anybody here ever heard of a writer
－该死的东西 －没听过？
-called Edgar Allan Poe? -No?
－没人听过 行了吗？ －你旁边根本没人
-No one. There you go. -I know there's no one there.
大家都在家工作
They are all working from home.
－马丁在啊 －这就是他的鬼主意
-Martin's here. -This was his idea!
识别证已经做好了
Well, the card's already been laminated.
好吧 我承认‥
All right, look, I grant you that 90%
西区九成的夜班保全
of the security guards working the night shift
不知道埃德加爱伦坡是谁
in the West End would not have heard of Edgar Allan Poe.
－把他们当机器搞定就行了 －但我很倒霉
-Basically dealing with robots. -But I am an unlucky person.
－命运老爱捉弄我 －识别证已经做好了
-Fate has a way of doing these little experiments on me. -Card's already laminated
马丁也做好你的新制服名牌了
and Martin has a new name badge made for your uniform.
－全装在一个信封裡 －就算我承认‥
-It's all in the envelope. -By some chance,
这个忧郁 内省的黑暗传播者
choosing the name of a gloomy,introspective peddler of darkness is actually
名字跟我挺搭
quite appropriate to my character,
但我拜托你
but please...
给我换一张不同名的识别证
just give me a new card under a different name.
机器人才不管你叫啥名字 只会看照片
The robots don't give a fuck about the name,they just look at the photo.
今晚六点到塞尔福裡的卸货口Ｂ
You are due at Selfridges' loading bay B at 1800 hours tonight.
穿上别著新名牌的制服
Wear your uniform with your name tag.
－亮出识别证 －我‥
-Flash your ID. -I....
你如果想退出 现在就说
Look, if you want to back out, say so now.
我不能再闯祸了 好吗？
I can't get into trouble again, all right?
我可能会被冠上‥
This could be construed as deception
诈欺以及窃盗未遂罪
and attempted robbery.
你要浪费我的时间 我就不跟你耗了 混帐
You counted me down,I'll count you down, you fucker.
五 四 三 二‥
Five, four, three, two...
该死 好啦‥我干就是了
Fuck! All right, all right. I'll do it.
很好 详细资讯在简讯裡
Good.Details are on the text.
愿主保佑你 帕斯顿
God bless you, Paxton.
不用签收 我认识他
No need to sign. I know him.
你是他太太吗？
Are you his other half?
是的 我是
Yes, yes, I am.
－他很无趣 对吧？ －对
-He's so dry, isn't he? -Yes, he is.
你好 帕斯顿
Hello, Paxton.
我正说到你很幽默
I was just saying you're very funny.
我知道 我超搞笑
Yes, I am. I am hilarious.
你开货车真是大材小用了
We think he's too clever to be driving vans.
不懂你为何不找个更好的工作
We don't know why he doesn't get a better job.
答案很简单
Well, that's easy.
愚蠢如我 十年前在 沃福的飞车党餐馆揍了人
It's 'cause ten years ago, I beat a man senseless in a bikers' roadhouse in Watford.
看吧？ 他老是说蠢话
See?He's always saying silly things.
超没哏的
He's so dry.
帮我跟马丁问好 薇吉妮雅
Give my regards to Martin, would you, Virginia?
－告诉他 我记下了 －好
-Tell him this won't be forgotten. -Okay.
等疯狂的时期结束再见了
See you when the madness is over.
对某些人来说 疯狂是家常便饭
Yeah, well, for some of us, the madness never ends.
记住 被你揍是他活该
Never forget, the man you beat senseless deserved it.
那不是你能决定的
Please don't talk about people deserving things.
若不是你 那个叫 阿契布鲁斯的小家伙早死了
If it wasn't for you, a little man called Archie Bruce would be dead.
所以呢 我要击鼓申冤吗？
What you want, justice next?
我知道你摔了大跟头
I know that you had a bad break,
－但你得振作‥ －振作？
- but going forward... - "Going forward"?
封城结束我们就会分开
When lockdown is over and we are apart,
拜托你不要再怨天尤人了
you have to stop believing that fate is against you. Okay?
别再怪”帕斯顿” 这个名字害你倒霉
You have to stop believing the name Paxton
”埃德加爱伦坡” 但我不叫帕斯顿
is a precursor of doom.Yes, well, my name isn't Paxton.
没错
Yeah.
公对公 埃德加爱伦坡
帕斯顿 那行不通 你会被抓的
Paxton, you can't go through with this, you're gonna get caught.
你想要钱我可以给你
If you're doing it for cash, I'll give you the cash.
我不是为了钱
I am not doing it for the cash.
－不然呢？ －我是为了过更好的生活
-Otherwise? -I'm doing it for the opportunity to have a better life.
这干你什麽事？
But why am I telling you?
”埃德加爱伦坡” 该死
Paxton.Fuck.
管他们去死
Fuck 'em.
琳达好像很抽离
And Linda seemed kind of detached from the whole thing.
很抽离？
Detached?
－你好 琳达 －我们正好聊到你
-Hi, Linda. -We were talking about you.
我们很敬佩你的敬业精神
We were all just saying that we love that you're always so professional.
等等 很抽离是什麽意思？
Detached from what whole thing?
我的意思是 你处理壹凡资一事时很理性
I was saying you handled the situation with Events without too much feeling getting in the way.
你很会开除人
You fired them well.
的确 多谢称赞
I did. Thank you.
很好
Good.
琳达 你在喝葡萄酒吗？
Linda, is that a glass of wine?
是啊 这个嘛‥
Oh, yes, yeah, it is.
标签上写葡萄酒 但喝起来像清洁用液体
it says wine on the label but it tastes like something used to clean something off of a surface.
－帕斯顿选的 －帕斯顿是哪位？
-Paxton chose it. -Who's Paxton?
回归正题
Mmm, anyway...
我们有问题得解决 开始吧
we have a problem, so shall we get on?
你好 马丁
Hello, Martin.
你好 埃德加
Hello, Edgar.
自我加入公司以来对你的观察
You know, from my observation of you since I joined the company,
你打破神经衰弱发作 最完美又最持久的纪录了
you represent the longest and most well-managed nervous breakdown in history.
还不快进屋裡发你的牢骚
Why don't you go somewhere warm and count your grievances?
我帮你消毒好厢型车了
I've disinfected the van for you.
你需要的都在这裡面
Everything you need is in there.
马侃说要给你二区的安全许可时
You know, when Malcolm told me he was giving you an A2 security clearance,
我跟他说最好不要
I advised him against it.
公对公不让你这种败类罪犯 处理高价货物是有道理的
B2B normally keep lowlifes like you away from high-value cargo for a reason...
－受不了诱惑 －你忘记放车钥匙了 马丁
-Temptation. -You forgot to put the keys to the van inside the envelope, Martin.
我看了你的人资档案
I've read your human resources profile.
我的个人经历应该是机密才对
My personal record is meant to be confidential,
但更新一下你的资讯 马丁
but for your personal record, Martin,
我跟以前不同了 把该死的钥匙拿来
I'm a different person now. Give me the fucking keys.
马侃可能没跟你说
Perhaps Malcolm didn't tell you.
今晚塞尔福裡的货 估价是五万英镑
The estimated value of tonight's cargo out of Selfridges is ￡50,000.
你周五从夏菲尼高运的那批
The value of your collection from Harvey Nichols on Friday
将近十万
is just under ￡100,000.
但周六晚上你要去哈洛德
But on Saturday night,when you go to Harrods,
从世上最奢侈的百货公司运货
you'll be driving away from the world's most glamorous department store
载著超过三百万英镑的 珠宝跟饰品离开
with jewelry and accessories in your van worth over three million pounds.
想想看 你会戴著口罩和手套
Now think on this.You'll be wearing a mask and gloves,
用假身份
you'll be using a false identity.
街上空无一人
Outside, the streets will be empty.
商店区的保全缺勤 处处是漏洞
Store security on quarter staff with big holes caused by absences.
根本是罪犯窃盗的最佳时机
What more could a lowlife need to pull off the perfect robbery.
你敢再叫我罪犯一次‥
You refer to me as "lowlife" one more time...
你就怎样 犯罪吗？
You'll what? Revert to type.
好吧 我再说一次
Okay, here goes, one more time.
罪犯
Lowlife.
马侃说接下来几晚 你若干得不错
You know, Malcolm told me that if you do okay in the next few nights,
他就要把你调去客服
he's gonna put you in customer services.
出去见客户
Goin' out and meeting clients.
因为你又酷又幽默
'Cause you're so funny
超会逗女生
and you're so dry and you make the girls laugh.
而我却困在派遣部七年半
Whereas I've been stuck in dispatches for seven and a half years.
别老觉得全世界跟你有仇 马丁
You have to stop thinking the whole world's against you, Martin.
下手吧 帕斯顿
Do it, Paxton.
顺从天意 接纳你的命运
Take the opportunity that fate has given you.
公对公专业货运公司
伊芙许沃 在哈洛德的商品总价多少？
Exactly how much product do Eve Schwarz have in Harrods?
大约三百万英镑的珠宝和饰品
Uh, approximately three million pounds' jewelry and accessories.
我们要负责帮哈洛德全部清空
Harrods wants everything out of the store and it's our responsibility...
你停格了 琳达
Oh, you've frozen, Linda.
听得到吗？
Can you hear me?
听得到 只是画面定格了
Yeah, I can hear you, just your face is frozen.
卡在你恼火的表情
You've got this look of exasperation.
因为得有人去哈洛德打包商品
Uh, someone's gonna have to go into Harrods and pack the valuables up
清点并剔除多余的品项
and check the inventory and count everything out.
而且要找值得信赖的人
And it's gonna have to be someone that we trust.
必须熟悉存货 还有哈洛德的运作方式
Someone who is familiar with the stock,and knows how the Harrods system works.
所以那个人就是我 对吧？
So that means, inevitably, it's going to be me, isn't it?
好吧 但打给你还有另一个目的
Okay, but there's this, another second reason for this call.
麦克埃辛决定给你升迁
Michael Essien has decided. He wants to give you a promotion.
他想调你回老家
He wants to bring you home.
回纽约管理东岸
Back to New York to run the East Coast.
天啊
Wow, God. Um...
很兴奋吧？
Exciting.
的确是跟便宜葡萄酒 很不搭调的惊喜
A unexpected turn of events and cheap wine don't pair well together.
我得好好考虑一下这件事
Um, I'm gonna have to, uh, really think about this.
好吧 晚安
Uh, right, good night.
我是指谢谢‥
Yeah, thank you.
看来琳达很激动‥
Linda, it's exciting...
卡在恼火的表情
A frozen look of exasperation.
那就是他的二儿子 卡尔菲利普艾曼纽巴哈
...and that is his second son, Carl Philipp Emauel Bach
请聆听他的第四号交响曲
and here's his Symphony No. 4.
昨晚通话后 我们有点担心 帕斯顿的心理状态
It's just that after our call last night,we became worried about Paxton's state of mind.
他可能会内爆或是爆发
We worry that he might implode or explode.
我们认识的帕斯顿大概是内爆
Knowing Paxton, he'll probably implode rather than explode.
－有什麽差别？ －内爆的人会封闭自己
-What's the difference? -When you implode, you withdraw within yourself,
爆发则是向外宣洩
when you explode, you impose yourself on the outer world.
拿大卫来说 他生气时会内爆
David, for example, when he gets angry, he implodes.
－但我生气时会爆发 －必要时我也会爆发
-When I get angry, I explode. - I can also explode if I have to.
－很少吧 －你肯定没看我开过商务会议
- Rarely. -You've obviously never seen me in business meetings.
封城后我其实看过
Well, actually I have. Since lockdown.
你只是隔牆听 没看
You've heard me through the wall, you haven't seen me.
好吧 我没”听”过你爆发 我其实很意外‥
Okay, then, I haven't heard you explode.I've actually been very surprised
－你在会议上那麽听话 －听话？
-about how submissive you are in meetings. - Submissive?
老板要有老板的样子 大卫
You're the boss, David, you should act like the boss.
好吧 我只是想说帕斯顿没事
Anyway, just to reassure you, Paxton's okay.
而且他可能要升迁了
In fact, Paxton maybe getting a promotion.
琳达 你一个人喝酒吗？
Linda, are you drinking alone?
没有 厨房有三个消防员在等我
No, I've got three firemen waiting for me in the kitchen.
封城后大卫开始狂喝
Since lockdown, David has been drinking so much more.
干得好 大卫 感觉很好吧？
Yes, David, isn't it wonderful?
我们现在会计算酒瓶量
We now keep a record. We count the bottles.
－我其实不在乎 －但你的身体在乎
- I don't care. - Your body cares.
你的肝髒一瓶一瓶记著呢
Your body counts the bottles and keeps an inventory in you liver.
大卫 我的酒友啊
David, my fellow drinker,
跟你说个秘密
I'd like to tell you a secret.
－什麽秘密？ －听著 琳达
- What secret? - You know, Linda,
我喝了几杯酒 隔天醒来后的反应通常是
my life where I've had a few glasses of wine and in the next morning,
”天啊 我不该说那种话”
I woke up like, "Golly. Wow. I wish I hadn't said that."
我也常常那样
Oh, I've done that so many times, too.
我的座右铭是 别用秘密配葡萄酒
You know, my mantra is, secrets and wine don't go great together.
－让她讲完秘密 －他会喜欢这个秘密
- Let her tell me the secret. -I think he's gonna like this secret.
－你会喜欢这个秘密 大卫 －你不懂他喜欢什麽
-I think you're gonna like this secret, David, very much. -Something he's gonna like, you don't know.
－他可能不喜欢 －你们到底在讲什麽？
- No, he might not. - What the fuck are you two talking about?
他现在不正常 他会看福斯
He might not be in a place where it's okay. He watches Fox.
是我要买帕斯顿的重机
It is I who am buying Paxton's motorbike.
什麽？
What?
他说要卖时 我就安排了匿名的买家
When he said he was selling it,I arranged a dealer to buy it anonymously.
我要买下来还给他
I'm gonna buy it and give it back to him.
作为分手礼物
My parting gift.
我知道我必须离开他 但‥
For a while I've known I had to leave him.But...
但失去重机是件大事
But losing the bike, yeah, that's too much.
而且我也重视那辆重机
And the bike means something to me, too.
青春嘛
You know, youth.
香烟跟帕斯顿选的超烂葡萄酒
Cigarettes. Bad, bad wine chosen by Paxton.
－琳达 那很好 －大卫 我想要你跟他说
- But here's the thing, David. I want you to tell him - Linda, that's awesome.
重机是你买的 由你还给他
that it's you who is buying the bike and giving it back to him.
别让他知道是我
I don't want him to know that it's me.
为什麽？
Why?
这样他好受一点
It'll hurt him less.
他挺古板的
He really is quite prehistoric.
我有点醉了 而且‥
I'm a bit drunk and I hate people
我讨厌为了这种事哭哭啼啼
who get emotional on these things,
我先‥
so...
该死
Fuck.
为国家健保局欢呼
Making noise for the
国家健保局‥
NHS.
你现在聆听的是 贝多芬第三号钢琴协奏曲
We've got Beethoven's Piano Concerto No. 3.
睡不著
Couldn't sleep.
喝酒没用 就去舔花园的罂粟吧
If the wine didn't work, go and lick the garden.
今晚如何？
How was it tonight?
我遇到的保全都是小学生
Every security person I met was under the age of 12,
大家都忙著打电玩
and every one of them was too busy playing Fortnite
没空仔细核实身份
to fully acknowledge my ID.
对年轻一代来说 文学巨作就是木乃伊
Anyway, I think for the young generation, great literature is dead.
依我看 识别证上写 ”威廉莎士比亚”也能过关
I could have had an ID card with William Shakespeare on it.
你还要送几趟？
How many more pick-ups do you have?
明天要去夏菲尼高接一件
Um, tomorrow, Harvey Nichols
周六哈洛德一件
and then, Saturday, Harrods.
周六去哈洛德？
Harrods? Saturday night?
外面一片混乱
It's all gone mad out there.
有个保全告诉我
One of the security guards was telling me about franchise managers
加盟经理把鑽戒和手表 装进塑胶袋
are taking out diamond rings and watches in plastic bags
然后叫车离开
and getting into Ubers.
你要去哈洛德百货接什麽货？
What are you taking out of Harrods?
不知道 马丁说东西 价值超过三百万英镑
I don't know.Martin says it's over three million pounds worth.
因为疫情关系 没有副驾驶
No co-drivers 'cause of COVID.
要载去哪裡？
Carrying it to where?
移交纪录说是希斯洛机场 十点飞纽约的班机
Uh, the docket says Heathrow. Ten o'clock flight to New York.
哈洛德百货到希斯洛 周六晚上
Harrods to Heathrow, Saturday night,
三百万英镑 十点的班机
three million pounds, ten o'clock flight.
快看 刺蝟在那边
Look, there's the hedgehog.
跑掉了
Oh, no, he's gone.
不见了
Ah, he's gone.
你今晚过得如何？
How was your evening?
帕斯顿 听我说
Okay, um, Paxton. Here it is.
你周六晚上 不能去哈洛德接货
You can't do that pick-up at Harrods on Saturday.
真的不行
You really can't.
你在说什麽？
What are you talking about?
记得吗 我曾问过 你信不信上帝
Okay, do you remember once I asked you,do you believe in God,
你说你认为 祂在忙别的企划
and you said that you believe that he's busy on another project,
但偶尔会关注一下这个世界
but occasionally he puts his head around the door?
我认为这就是那种状况
Well, I think this may be one of those occasions,
因为神 命运或病毒 或什麽人让我们困在一起
'cause God or fate or the virus or somebody put our paths on the cross.
星期六 我会在哈洛德 打包你要运送的货物
On Saturday, I will be in Harrods packing up the cargo that you are due to carry.
该死
Fuck.
你在说什麽‥？
What are you talkin' about? I...
我必须去载货
I have to do the pick-up.
你若去就会被逮到
If you do, you will be caught.
你用什麽名字都没差 那是假名
It doesn't matter what name you're using.
我让系统进行交叉检查 你根本进不了门
It's a fake name and I have implemented cross-checks.You won't make it past the door.
我知道 因为会是我的系统挡下你
I know, because it's my system that will stop you!
对不起 该死 什麽都别说
I'm sorry. And what the fuck, don't even begin.
我哪儿都去不成
I can't fucking get anywhere!
我是说‥
I mean...
你不能就告诉他们 你认识我吗？
Can't you just tell them that you know me?
就说你知道能信任我 我是‥
That you know I can be trusted. That I am your...
我曾是你的伴侣
That I was your partner.
－干嘛啦？ －不能那样做事
- What? - It doesn't work like that.
而且我‥
And I...
自三年前进了米拉克后 我都没跟人提过我有伴侣
Since joining Miracore three years ago,I haven't told anyone I have a partner.
部分是因为我想区分公私
Partly because I wanted to keep work separate.
但主要是你觉得 伴侣开货车很丢脸
Yeah, but mostly because you were embarrassed to have a partner that drives a van.
对 以上都是
Yes. All of the above. I...
但现在我在自省
But now, I am looking at myself.
自封城后 我好好自省
Since lockdown, I'm looking back at myself
区分了过去与现在的心态
like that was then and this is now.
很好啊 琳达 但我周六晚上若不去载货
Well, good for you, Linda,but if I don't make this collection on Saturday night,
马侃不只不会帮我升职
then, not only will Malcolm not promote me,
他会开除我
he will fire me.
我总可以开始卖海洛因
I could always start dealing heroin.
败类就是败类
Lowlife is lowlife.
没工作 没机车
No job. No bike.
也没有你
No you.
我在哈洛德百货工作时很开心
When I worked at Harrods, I had so much fun.
我和大家都互相认识
I knew everyone. Everyone knew me.
－很多人都还在‥ －话题能不能先回到我身上？
Most of them still work there... -Is there any possibility
－完蛋的是我 －不是的 这的确跟你有关
-we might get back to me for a moment? -No, no, this is about you.
我认识所有保全
All right, I know all the security guards, everyone.
－我很了解保全系统 －所以呢？
- I know the security systems. - So?
所以有办法让你去哈洛德接货 并安全送到希斯洛机场
So there is a way for you to make your pick-up deliver to Heathrow without getting caught.
你能够升迁 我也能搬走存货
You will get your promotion and I will get my stock removed
没人会知情
and no one will know.
但那样会违法
But we will be breaking the law.
所以你要完全照我说的做
So you're gonna have to do absolutely everything I tell you to do.
我是麦可摩根 哈洛德活动保全副组长
Michael Morgan. Acting Deputy Head, Harrods' Events Security.
对 你在我以前的部门
Yes, you are in my old department.
在哈洛德过得如何？
How's life at Harrods?
我才刚加入 我以前在海军
I only just joined. I used to be in the Royal Navy.
差别满大的呢
Oh, quite a change then.
也不会 哈洛德就像是一艘大船
Not really. No, Harrods is like a big ship.
了解
Oh. Okay.
当然是有些很大的差别
I mean, there are, obviously, huge differences.
当然了
Of course.
是啊 不只是建筑物的形状
Yeah, and not just in terms of the shape of the building
或是百货不会漂浮这点
or the fact that it doesn't float.
－就是‥ －对
- You know, it's... - Oh, yeah.
工作环境一定很不一样
Yeah, the working environment must be very different, I imagine.
没错 这儿很多女性
Yes, it is. Lot of women here.
对‥
Yes.
船上只有四位女性
Yeah, on the ship, there was only four.
其中两位都叫凯伦
And, uh, two of them were called Karen.
我们叫她们 凯伦一号和二号
Called them Karen one and Karen two.
凯特好像应该出席？
I think Kate's meant to be joining us?
对 壹凡资的凯特史密斯
Kate Smith, yes, from Events.
我们认识时她还姓怀利 她一定是结婚了
When I knew her, she was Kate Wiley.She must have gotten married.
她的确结婚了 但婚姻好像很糟
Yeah, she did get married, yeah, but it all went horribly wrong, I think.
真是遗憾 不知道发生什麽事了
Oh, sorry to hear that.What happened?
不知道 他们不跟我聊那种事
I don't know. They don't talk to me about that sort of thing.
琳达
Linda!
凯蒂？
Katie!
天啊‥你好吗？
Oh my God, Oh, my God. How are you?
－天哪 你也知道‥ －琳达 你简直扶摇直上
-Oh, my gosh. You know, I'm surviving. -Linda, you have gone off like a rocket!
－少来啦 －我的老天
- Oh, stop. - I mean, my God.
当他们提到米拉克总裁 我以为会是个秃头男
When they said CEO Miracore,I thought, "Okay, God, some bald man,"
但接著我看到你的名字
but then I saw your name.
琳达刚刚问到 你的婚姻怎麽了
Linda was just asking what went wrong with your marriage. She...
没有 我没问‥
No. No, no, no. I wasn't. I didn't.
当男人比你矮
When a man is shorter than you
又突然决定要留大胡子
and then suddenly decides to let his beard grow very, very long
接著又迷上所谓的”白魔法”
and then becomes obsessed with so called "white magic,"
很快就会变得很诡异
it can just get very creepy very quickly.
回归正题 我们能如何为你效劳？
Anyway, what can we do for you?
我接到周六 伊芙许沃清出库存的消息
I have an update about the Eve Schwarz clear-out on Saturday.
所有安全的货运公司都订满了 看来我们的物流部门慢了一步
You see, all the secure freight companies have been booked and it looks like our logistics
伊芙许沃 米拉克 请看资料
Eve Schwarz, Miracore. Here it is.
他们预约了 我没用过的货运公司
They've booked a freight company that I've never used before,
所以我很担忧
so that's why I'm anxious.
标莱姆绿的‥
Lime green is the color and, uh...
－你担心那家货运公司？ －会有绿色箭头指向‥
-So you're anxious about the freight company? -It's gonna be green arrows pointing...
如果可以的话
So if it's okay with you,
我了解哈洛德的保全系统 我想亲自检查司机
I know the Harrods security system and I'd like to run the checks on the driver myself.
不用啦 那是伊姆兰的工作
Oh, no, no, that's Imran's job. That's...
记得伊姆兰吗 琳达？
Do you remember Imran, Linda?
－我好喜欢他‥ －他现在是壹凡资保全主管
-I love Imran... -Imran is now head of Events security.
－他是麦可的上司 －你有什麽问题我都能处理
-He's Michael's boss. -You got any questions. I can handle everything.
－我现在传简讯给他 －不用 拿箭头的是我‥
-Let me text him now. -Don't, I'm gonna be the one with the arrows. So...
好了 搞定
Okay. Done.
明天我亲自用系统跑你的资料 然后让你进入百货
Tomorrow, I'll run you through the system myself and then get you into the store.
在那之后还能出什麽错？
After that, what can go wrong?
太棒了 感谢
Hey, great. Thanks.
真的很感谢你为我这麽做
I really appreciate you doing this for me.
－怎麽了？ －我不知道
- What's the matter? - I don't know.
日子过得很快
Days are passing quickly.
我今早醒来时 第一次深深意识到这点
When I woke up this morning,it really hit me for the first time.
我意识到了此时的现实
The reality of what's happening hit me.
封城总有一天会结束
The lockdown will eventually end.
然后‥
Then...
我就会失去此生挚爱
the love of my life will be gone.
帕斯顿 你会放下这件事的 你会走出情伤
Paxton, you will move on from this. You will heal.
我的人生会多出巨大的空缺
There'll be a huge hole in my life.
你会改变与成长
You'll change and grow. And...
最后你会‥
Eventually you'll...
你会遇见新对象
you'll meet someone else.
你说的是那辆机车 对吧？
You were talking about the bike, weren't you?
对 干嘛问？
Yeah. Why?
那辆机车是我人生的挚爱之一
The bike is one of the loves of my life.
－而我是空缺？ －你当然是最大的空缺
-And I am one of the holes? -Obviously you're the biggest hole.
真是谢谢你
Oh, why, thank you.
我今天本来要牵车出去
I was gonna take the bike out today.
街上空无一人
The streets are completely deserted.
我本来要趁封城疯最后一回
I was gonna call it "Lockdown-one-last-ride."
我想说‥
I thought maybe...
我不能跟你去 帕斯顿
Oh, no, I can't go with you, Paxton.
我有场重要的会议
No. I have an important meeting.
开阔的道路和一颗破碎的心
An open road and a broken heart.
骑车小心点
Don't kill yourself.
－琳达 －麦克
- Linda! - Michael.
你都还好吗？
How are you coping?
挺不好过的
You know, it's been quite difficult.
完全能想像
I can imagine.
我在山顶上隔离
You know, I'm locked up on a mountaintop
只有老鹰 熊 还有家人跟我作伴
with only eagles and bears and my family for company.
拜托别自杀
Please don't kill yourself.
什麽？
What?
我说能有独处时间一定很棒
I said it must be nice to have time to yourself.
总之 在我们讨论 你回到纽约的重大决定前
Anyway, before we get on to the exciting business decision to come home to New York,
有个好消息 哈裡斯鑽石有买家了
the good news is that we have found a buyer for the Harris Diamond.
其实我还没决定要回纽约
Uh, actually, I haven't decided to come home to New York.
买家在线上介绍看到鑽石
The buyer saw the diamond on the virtual presentation
就是你在发表会前做的介绍
that you put together ahead of the store takeover.
太棒了 买家是谁？
That's great. Who is it?
琳达啊 在我们的新世界 是不问买家身份的
In our new world, Linda,one does not ask who.
他是匿名的 但我能告诉你
He's anonymous.But I can tell you this. He's, um...
他是某个讨厌的家族 令人讨厌的成员
A very unpleasant member of a very unpleasant family
那个家族用可怕的方式 统治一个讨厌的国家
who run a very unpleasant country in a very unpleasant way.
他让米拉克 在他的国家做生意
He is facilitating Miracore in his country
所以我亲自促成了这桩买卖
and so I've brokered the purchase of the diamond personally.
哈洛德不愿意跟他扯上关系
Harrods themselves will have nothing to do with him,
所以我就当中间人
so I have acted as go-between.
我们好棒 对吧？
Hurray for us, no?
对 我们好棒
Yes, hurray for us.
他会想亲自来拿鑽石吗？
Uh, will he be wanting to pick up the diamond in person?
他不得入境英国
He is not allowed into the UK.
好像是跟‥
Something to do with, um...
洗钱有关 还是侵犯人权？
Money laundering? Human rights abuses?
总之 重要的问题
Anyway, the big question, Linda,
目前要讨论的议题 是琳达的未来
the issue at hand here is the future of Linda.
你什麽时候回家？
When will you be coming home?
我决定等封城结束 再决定要不要回纽约
Well, I've decided to leave my decision about New York until after lockdown is lifted.
我在伦敦有很多认识的人
I have lots of ties in London.
我听说你单身
Uh-huh. I was told that you're single.
其实不是的
Actually, that was never true,
但现在真的单身了
but actually now it is.
你单身是我希望 你来纽约的理由之一
The fact that you are single is one of the reasons I want you to come to New York.
我打算好好了解你
I'm planning to get to know more about you.
你令我著迷 琳达
You...You fascinate me, Linda.
表面上如此强悍
So tough on the outside,
但你的内心也如此吗？
but inside,are you tough?
你还记得你到巴黎的时候吗？
Do you remember when you came to Paris?
开完会的那个晚上
That evening, after the meeting,
我本来要带你去吃晚餐
I was going to take you out to dinner.
我那晚本来想诱惑你的
I was actually going to try to seduce you that night.
我想不到那个晚上会怎麽样
Well, I can only speculate what kind of evening that might have been.
但我猜可能会有碎玻璃
But I suspect it would have involved broken glass.
总之 我该把鑽石寄送到 可能杀人如麻的老兄家裡
Anyway, uh, should I send the diamond to this probable mass murderer's home
还是直接送到他的拷问密室？
or should I send it straight to his torture chamber?
什麽？
What?
我要把鑽石寄去哪裡？
Where would you like me to send the diamond?
寄到纽约
Ah, send it to New York.
因为疫情关系
Um, because of COVID,
鑽石会直接送进 华尔街的安全金库
it will be couriered directly to a safe vault in Wall Street.
那裡没人能检查货品
There'll be no one to check it there,
所以请确保证明文件 都装在盒子裡
so please make sure that the verification papers are in the box.
知道了吗？
Got that?
对我们很多的新客户来说
For many of our new wave of clients,
收购之举本身就是结果
the act of acquisition is an end in itself.
纽约见 琳达 保重
Okay. See you in New York, Linda. Take care.
我‥
Well, I...
别闹了 琳达
Don't be ridiculous, Linda.
由于医疗用口罩缺货 民众用旧衣服自制口罩
A shortage of medical masks,people are making their own from old clothing.
但世卫组织表示 不确定自制口罩是否‥
But the WHO said it doesn't know whether homemade masks...
你去哪儿了？
Hey.Where'd you go?
佩克汉莱
Peckham Rye.
－为什麽？ －不知道
- Why? - I don't know.
－什麽叫你不知道？ －我骑得很快
-What do you mean, you don't know? -I was just driving really, really fast,
因为警察追著我
because I was being chased by the police.
－什麽？ －我在玩封城新游戏
- What? - I was playing a new lockdown game.
绿灯停 红灯行
Green for stop, red for go.
要死了
Fuck!
－他们看到你的车牌号码了吗？ －没有 我骑太快了
-Did they get your license number? -No, I'm too fast for 'em.
我是空城中 空荡荡道路上的一道光
I'm a streak of light on an empty road in a deserted city.
我是世上最后一个人
I'm the last man alive.
我任由道路带领我
I let the road direct me and I achieved that moment
达到了机车与人一体的绝妙境界
of transcendence where the bike becomes part of your body.
我来到了南伦敦 某个有可爱动物园的都会农场
I found myself in South London on some sort of urban farm with a petting zoo
我躲在山羊群裡
and I hid among the goats.
记得吧 我们当异教徒时 山羊是我的图腾动物
Remember the goat was my totem animal when we were pagans.
我跟山羊坐在一起
I sat with the goats and then resumed
警车疾驶而过后 我继续踏上旅程
my journey as the police cars drove past.
我去了佩克汉
I was in Peckham.
我给你买了香烟
I bought you cigarettes.
自己也抽了一根
And I had one myself.
我十年来抽的第一根真烟
My first real, real one in ten years.
你说得对 烟草有青春的味道
And you were right, tobacco tastes like youth!
真货就是真货 我爱的是真烟草
And real is real, and real tobacco is me really,
我现在就想再来一根 我要抽了
and I want another one right now and I'm gonna have one.
我好久都没见过 你现在的眼神了
You have a look in your eyes I haven't seen in a long time.
我不是故意要吓你
I don't mean to frighten you.
我没有吓到
I'm not frightened.
记得我跟你说过 巴黎的玻璃马和骑师吗？
Remember I told you about the glass horse and jockey in Paris?
不记得 我还在想那些山羊
No, I'm still with the goats.
它们的眼睛是蓝的
They had blue eyes.
我抓著雕像骑师的部分 然后转了一圈‥
I held the horse and jockey by the jockey and swung it around and...
我想起了当骑士的感觉
And I remembered how it felt to be a rider
跟你骑著的东西 合为一体的感受
and to feel like you're a part of the thing that you are riding.
那是一种如性爱的感觉
It's a sexual feeling.
没错
Yeah, it is.
我现在后悔没跟你去了
I now wish I'd come with you.
是吗？
Really?
帕斯顿
Paxton,
很久以来 我都知道我们结束了
for a long time, I've known that our relationship was over.
很长一段时间 我们之间只剩下性
And for a long time, the only unbroken thread between us has been sex.
继续说
Go on.
我觉得这一刻十分难耐
I'm finding this moment difficult because...
因为我发誓过 不会发生这种事
I made a vow this wouldn't happen,
你能不能脱掉皮外套 去拿一条茶巾？
so could you just take the leather jacket off and go hold a tea towel or something?
－拿茶巾？ －或去买牛奶 那就帮大忙了
- Hold a tea towel? - Or buy some milk, it would help me.
－我们有牛奶了 －或烤面包
- We have milk. - Or bake bread.
那样绝对能破坏气氛
That would definitely kill the moment.
我只想骑上机车 尽情驰骋
I just want to get on my bike and ride
管全世界去死
and fuck the world.
好了 帕斯顿 是这样的
Okay, Paxton, here it is.
这可能是封城造成的
Probably as a result of lockdown,
你产生了骑车闯红灯的疯狂冲动
you have a mad urge to ride your motorbike through red lights.
而两小时前 我也有股疯狂冲动
And as of two hours ago, I have a mad urge
想从杀人魔手中 偷走价值三百万英镑的鑽石
to steal a diamond worth three million pounds from a mass murderer
－然后辞掉工作 当艺术家 －什麽？
-and quit my job and become an artist. -What?
但我觉得要发洩这股疯狂冲动 最实际的做法
But I think the most practical thing we can do to get this madness out of our system
就是我打破誓言
is that I break my vow
然后我们立刻上楼去做爱
and we go upstairs right now and have sex.
封城最后疯一回
"Lockdown-one-last-ride."
先是山羊 现在又这样
Goats, now this.
今天真够精彩
What a fucking day.
你好‥
Hi. Yeah,
她在换衣服
she's, uh, she's just changing.
对了
Oh, by the way,
你听过一个诗人 埃德加爱伦坡吗？
you ever heard of a poet called Edgar Allan Poe?
－什麽？ －算了 没事
- What? - Yeah, never mind.
等一下
All right. One second.
您收听的是 ”和多明尼克开车”
You're listening to Drive Time with Dominic.
为您播放韩德尔的作品
And this is George Frideric Handel.
请挂断或按井字键 选择其他选项
Please hang up or press the hash key for more options.
琳达 我打来只是想说
Uh, Linda, I'm just calling to say that
我知道今天下午 没什麽特别意义
I know this afternoon didn't mean anything,
但我想告诉你 那感觉像是‥
but I want you to know that it would have felt like, uh...
南达科塔 那个下雨的下午
like South Dakota that afternoon when it rained.
我还有一段诡异的记忆
And also, I have this bizarre memory that just before
我们偏离正道之前 你提到要偷鑽石
we strayed from the path of righteousness,you said something about stealing a diamond.
你说什麽要偷鑽石
...you said something about stealing a diamond.
是我幻想的吗？
Did I imagine that?
－重播留言请按１‥ －天啊
-Press 1 to replay the message -Oh, God!
谢谢
Thank you.
没有 奶奶 我没打算认真考虑
No, Grandma, I am not seriously considering it.
该死
Fuck.
病患术后通常在此休养
This is where the patients usually recover post-surgery.
但现在必须收容加护病房 无法容纳的新冠肺炎患者
But now, it's needed for COVID-19 overflow from intensive care.
医院必须调整 空间使用方式及做法
Hospitals are having to adapt their spaces and practices
以因应新冠肺炎
to be able to deal with Coronavirus.
我在加护病房当护理师十八年了
I've been a nurse in ICU for 18 years
第一次遇到这种‥
and I've never seen...
好
All right.
重要的周六到了
Big Saturday.
哈洛德百货
Harrods.
展开大骗局
The grand deception.
跟我说明详细的流程
You have to tell me exactly what it is we have to do.
帕斯顿
Paxton...
先坐 等等我
Sit down. Wait there.
我只是想顺一顺我们的计划
This is just us organizing what it is that we're gonna do, okay?
不要想太多 好吗？
It's nothing else.
不然是可以想什麽？
Why, what else would it be?
没什麽 你干嘛问？
Nothing. Why do you ask?
－你还好吗？ －我？
-Are you okay? -Me?
我没事啊 完全没事
I am okay. I am intensely okay and normal.
说说场地
Okay. Background.
哈洛德百货
Harrods.
地表层都对外开放
The top part is the public area.
但地下还有七层楼
But below ground, there are seven floors.
这裡是货仓 有很多密道
Floors where merchandise is stored and lots of tunnels
珠宝等昂贵商品 会透过密道运至秘密电梯
where expensive items such as jewelry are transported to secure elevators.
地表上都很庄重奢华
All grown up and glamorous above
地面下则很有序而阴森
and efficient and scary below.
哈洛德的保全非常严密
Security at Harrods is unbelievably tight,
潜入偷窃根本是不可能的事
it would be impossible to get inside to actually steal something.
偷？
Steal?
谁说要偷东西了？
Who's talking about stealing anything?
冷静点 帕斯顿 不要大惊小怪好不好
Everything is normal. Paxton, stop being weird.
我才不是大惊小怪
It's not me being weird.
你分明别有用心 而且还欲盖弥彰
I mean, you clearly appear to have a hidden agenda,which is not really that hidden,
我不知道那是什麽 还有你的眼睛上有髒东西
but I don't know what it is.Also, you've got a smudge above your eye.
你昨晚收到我传的讯息了吗？
Did you get my message on your phone last night?
南达科他州的事？
About South Dakota?
还有鑽石的事
And about a diamond.
帕斯顿 你有什麽毛病？
Paxton, what is the matter with you?
－我没有毛病 －你认真？
- There's nothing the matter with me. - Seriously?
昨天你说要偷鑽石
Yesterday, you were talking about stealing a diamond.
你肯定说过 不是我自己乱想
You were, I'm not imagining it.
今天你就画出哈洛德的地图 好像有什麽秘密计划
And today, you are drawing Harrods like it's, uh,some kind of secret plan in
－好像劫盗片一样 －秘密计划哪会画那麽粗糙
-a secret heist movie. -How can you draw a rectangle like you're in a secret plan? I don't...
你有没有秘密计划嘛
Do you have a secret plan?
跟你说‥
You know...
我昨天见到我奶奶
I saw my grandmother's face yesterday.
我跟奶奶说我没问题
I told her, "It's okay, Grandma, I am fine.
绝对不会做出蠢事
I'm not going to do anything stupid."
你说那颗鑽石叫哈裡斯鑽石
You said the diamond is called a Harris Diamond.
拜托 帕斯顿
Oh, Paxton, come on.
今天是周六 天亮了
It's Saturday. It's morning.
凌晨四点的怪异幻想 早就烟消云散了
All the weird 4:00 a.m. fantasies and options have gone away as they always do.
那是怎样的鑽石？
Tell me about the diamond.
哈裡斯鑽石有两颗
There are two Harris Diamonds.
－什麽？ －哈裡斯鑽石有两颗 不懂吗？
- What? - There are two Harris Diamonds, okay. God!
为什麽有两颗？
Why are there two?
你以为我昨晚有睡吗？
Do you think I slept at all last night, Paxton?
没有 整晚没睡
Well actually, no, I didn't.
那你为什麽醒著？
And what was it that kept you awake?
哈裡斯鑽石一号
Harris Diamond one,
哈裡斯鑽石二号
Harris Diamond two.
一颗是真的
One is real,
另一颗是假的
the other is fake.
这种价位的鑽石不会展示真品
Whenever a diamond of this value is exhibited in store,
大家看到的一定是复制品
they use a replica of the real thing to put into the public area.
真品一定在金库的保险箱裡
The actual diamond is kept safe in the vaults.
现在复制品在这裡展示
Currently, the replica is on display here on
位在一楼
the ground floor.
但是真品放在这裡
But your real Harris Diamond is here in the vaults.
锁在金库
Tonight,
今晚七点整 保全会带我们进金库
at exactly 7:00 p.m.,you and I will be escorted to the vaults by security
拿取真正的哈裡斯鑽石
to collect the real Harris Diamond.
然后我们搭秘密电梯去一楼
We will then go up the ground floor in a secure elevator where we add the diamond
并在电梯内把鑽石 放入伊芙许沃典藏组中
to the rest of the Eve Schwarz collection.
到了七点半
Then, right there at 7:30 p.m.,
我们手中会有真品 跟以假乱真的复制品
we will have the real diamond and the very good replica diamond, side by side,
放一起的话 常人根本分不出真伪
next to each other, almost indistinguishable.
而因为疫情封城
And because of COVID restrictions,
只有你跟我两人会在场
the only people that will be there are you and me.
所以我们要把真的鑽石 放进保险箱 寄回纽约
So, then we put the real diamond into a secure box and send it to New York,
然后把玻璃复制品 放进我的包包 拿去丢掉
and we take the glass replica and I put it in my purse, we take it away for disposal,
这就是我们的完整流程 没有别的了
and that is what we are going to fucking do,exactly that and nothing else.
奶奶 我爱你
Grandma, I love you.
能问个很明显的问题吗？
May I ask a very obvious question?
不可以
No, you may not.
如果我们把复制品寄回纽约
What would happen if we sent the replica to New York
拿走真品
and kept the real thing?
我想鑽石寄达纽约后
I'm assuming that as soon as it got to New York,
一定会有人发现是假货吧
someone would realize that it was fake.
不会 没有人会发现
No, they wouldn't.
所以我才彻夜未眠
That is why I couldn't sleep.
不管我们寄哪一颗去纽约
Whichever one we send to New York,
都会被直接送进华尔街的金库
it will go into a secure vault in Wall Street
下次有人类看到它
and won't even be looked at by another human being
可能是二十 五十 百年后的事了
for 20, 50, 100 years.
老天啊
Holy fuck.
三百万英镑
Three million pounds, tax free.
不用抽税 不用付出代价
No consequences.
你一份 我一份 一份给健保局
One for me, one for you, one for the NHS.
－你明明动过贪念 －不行 我‥
-You have thought about this. -No, I can't
我要去冥想了
You know, I need to go meditate.
纽约真的不会检查吗？
Are you sure they won't check it in New York?
闭嘴 我要冥想
Shut up. I need to meditate.
你想表达什麽？
What were you going to say?
鑽石的买家是个恶人
The man who bought the diamond is bad.
他是大恶棍 我们俩是好人
He's really bad, and you and I are good.
健保也是好制度 全都比那个恶棍好
And the NHS is good. And good is better than bad.
我跟奶奶解释的时候 连她都说有道理
When I explained all that to Grandma,even she said, "Well, yeah, that's true."
她可是喀尔文教派的铁杆信徒
And she was a Calvinist, straight as a rod.
不像我 这麽容易受诱惑
Unlike me, who is weak in the face of temptation.
不放纵毋宁死 琳达
Live wild or die, Linda.
帕斯顿 你忘了一件很重要的事
Paxton, you're forgetting something very important, okay?
假设‥我们真的行动
Assuming that we do this thing,
我知道这不可能
which we definitely won't,
我们两个普通人
how would two ordinary people like you and me
去哪儿找门路 销赃三百万英镑的鑽石？
find a way to sell a three million pounds stolen diamond?
好的 就是这样 我使出浑身解数
Okay, that was it. That was my last attempt
说明我们不该做这种事
to find a logical reason why we shouldn't do this,
但你一定会说 找阿契布鲁斯 对吧？
but you are going to say "Archie Bruce," aren't you?
没错
Yes, I am.
阿契布鲁斯
Archie Bruce.
这几年我一直跟他有联系
Over the years, I've kept up with the guys.
阿契布鲁斯 从摩托车偷到老爷车
I mean, Archie Bruce,he's graduated from stealing motorcycles to stealing vintage cars
还偷艺术品跟珠宝
and fine art and jewelry.
他一定可以轻松把鑽石 卖到莫斯科的某个顶层公寓
I mean, he'd have Mr. Harris in a penthouse in Moscow before the banging of the next saucepans.
而且他一定会答应
And he'd do a preferential deal with you,
因为你那一晚挺身而出
because you stepped in one night and saved his life
在沃福的酒吧救了他的命
at a roadhouse in Watford.
某种因果轮回吧
Circle of life, something like that.
一切折磨因阿契而起
With Archie Bruce, the nightmare began.
现在由阿契来了结
Maybe with Archie Bruce, the nightmare ends.
所以‥
So,
我们要怎麽办 琳达？
what are we going to do, Linda?
好吧
Okay,
这样吧 帕斯顿
Paxton, here it is.
我们今晚决定
We decide tonight.
我们到哈洛德亲眼看到鑽石
When we're there at Harrods with the diamonds,
就会知道该怎麽做了
we're gonna know what's right and what's wrong.
我们当场决定
We'll decide in the moment.
或是顺其自然
Or let the moment decide.
有什麽不同？
What's the difference?
一个是宿命 一个是自由意志
Fate versus free will.
谁控制著我们的命运？
Who controls our destiny?
一切都早已注定 或者我们自己搞砸了？
Is everything part of a plan or do we fuck things up for ourselves?
今晚七点半就会知道了
Tonight at 7:30, we find out.
你好 半个兄弟
Hey, half-brother.
什麽 现在？
What, now?
你想要视讯？
You wanna Zoom?
好 等我一下
All right, give me a minute.
帕斯顿
Ah, Paxton,
你好吗？
how are you?
我现在有点犹豫不决
Actually, I am at a fork in the road.
是吗？
Really?
我要说的没准能帮你 决定选哪条路
Then perhaps what I have to say will have some bearing on which fork you take,
跟路还真有点关系
because it is sort of road related.
前几天你说要把重机卖掉
You see, Paxton, the other day when you said you want to sell your motorcycle,
我就说等等 别那麽急
I thought, "Wait a minute. Time out. Not so fast."
我挂掉电话之后
And then, after I cut the call
－就想到老妈 －老妈？
-I thought about Mom. -Mum?
你被迫卖掉最珍爱的东西 她会做何感想？
How she would feel about you having to sell
而我却在美丽的哈得孙谷快活
your most precious possession,while at the same time, over here
你的异父兄弟过得还不错
in the beautiful Hudson Valley,your brother, your half-brother isn't having it so bad.
果园的樱桃树长出蕈类
You know, when the cherry trees in your orchard get a fungus,
是很不妙 但还有更糟的事
it sucks, but there are worse things.
对樱桃树来说确实不是最糟
Yeah, not for the cherry tree.
对樱桃树来说 最糟的事 莫过于乔治华盛顿
Maybe worse for a cherry tree is the steady tread of George Washington
怀著好意拿著斧头出现
as he approaches with an axe in his hand and a head full of good intentions.
总之 我想到 老妈会希望我怎麽做
Anyway, I wondered what Mom would want me to do.
老妈应该会希望你长话短说
Well, remembering Mum,I think she'd want you to get to the point.
好吧 帕斯顿
Okay, Paxton,
我就说了
here it is.
你的宝贝重机是我买的
It is I who has bought your precious motorcycle.
重机的买家就是我
The purchaser of your bike is me.
我要把车还给你
And I am giving it back to you.
一点善意 同母异父的兄弟情
My gesture, half-brother to half-brother.
你的重机回到你手中了
Your bike is yours once more.
不要感谢我 帕斯顿
Don't thank me, Paxton.
真的 不需要
Please. No need.
我只有一件事有求于你
All I ask, the only thing I ask of you, Paxton,
请你从现在开始善待自己
is that you are kind to yourself from now on.
记取教训 你要明白世界不跟你作对
That you learn from this.That the world does not hate you.
没错 命运有时很捉弄人
That, yes, sometimes fate seems harsh and cruel,
但要知道人性本善‥
but people really do what good...
大卫 我是琳达 你好
Hey, David, it's Linda. Hi!
琳达 我正在跟帕斯顿讲话
Uh, Linda, I thought I was just speaking to Paxton.
我知道 我听见你的大善事了
Yes, I know. I heard, David, your magnificent gesture,
我实在情不自禁 一定要亲自跟你视讯
and I just... I couldn't stop myself,I couldn't help myself. I just had to jump on the call
告诉你我多感谢 你真是个大好人
and say, "Oh, my God, David.What kind of a person are you?"
大卫买了我的重机
David bought my fucking bike.
我听见了 也听见他说教
Yes, I heard. I heard, and then I heard the sermon,
他不只花钱不手软
and I thought, "Wow!Not only is he so generous with his cash,
还大方分享自己的智慧呢
he is so free with his wisdom."
－总之 帕斯顿‥ －别这样
- Anyway, Paxton, there it is... - No, no, no.
别让我打断这感人的一刻
Don't let me interrupt this meaningful moment.
大卫 你继续刚刚的大道理‥
What is it that you were saying, David?Something about fate being harsh and...
－你干嘛对他发火？ －我没有啊
-Why were you mad at him? -I wasn't mad.
明明就有
Yes, you were.
就是你
It was you.
你买走我的重机
You bought my bike.
帕斯顿 你乱讲什麽 你刚刚也听见了
Paxton, don't be ridiculous. You heard what David said.
大卫才不可能那麽好心 倒是很爱抢功劳
David would never do something like that,but he would take the credit.
你则会做好事 又让别人抢走功劳
Whereas you would do something like that and give the credit to someone else.
是因为你可怜我吧
You did it 'cause you felt sorry for me.
对 我很担心 你失去一切后会怎麽样
Yes, I worried about what would happen if you lost everything.
其实主要还是我的良心过不去
Mainly because I didn't want anything bad on my conscience.
但同时‥
Confession avalanche, but also I...
也因为这辆重机能代表我们
I did it because the bike represents us.
－才怪‥ －我是‥
- And... - No, no, no.
你就是可怜我
Pity is over here, all right,
离爱我还远得很
and love is way over here.
别假装两者间有一道桥
Don't pretend there is a bridge.
但你会可怜一个 盗窃数百万英镑的男人吗？
But would you still feel pity for a man who'd just stolen a million pounds?
我会一夜致富
I'd be a millionaire,
同时变回一个恶棍
and a bandido once again.
也许你会回心转意
Maybe you'd change your mind.
也许我们能一起骑向夕阳
Maybe we'd ride off into the sunset.
帕斯顿
Paxton...
不管我们今晚怎麽决定
whatever we decide to do tonight,
我们都会分道扬镳
we will go our separate ways.
有钱了 表示我们都自由了
The money would mean that we're both free.
好 这也许会影响我做的决定
Well, I will factor that into my decision-making process.
谢谢你的重机
Thanks for the bike.
各位先生女士
Ladies and gentlemen...
被隔离的同胞
fellow inmates...
我要送你们一份礼物
I have something for you
在我搭上２７路公车 去面对命运之前
before I head off on the number 27 bus to meet my destiny.
送你们一首诗的节选
It's a passage from a poem
艾略特写的
written by T.S. Eliot,
我想你们都没听过他
who I'm sure no one has ever heard of either.
”她向酒杯瞬间一瞥”
"She turns and looks a moment in the glass,
”全无留意告辞的爱人”
hardly aware of her departed lover.
”她的脑允一丝 半成的思绪通过‥”
Her brain allows one half-formed thought to pass.
”已然结束”
Well, now that's done,
”我为此欣喜”
and I'm glad it's over."
关键时刻见了 琳达
See you in the moment, Linda.
这可能是我此生 最后一次搭公车
This could be the last bus I ever take.
琳达
我决定自己过去了
Oh, I've decided to go by myself. Thanks.
－谢谢‥ －好的 没问题
- No problem. - Thank you.
动手吧 帕斯顿
Do it, Paxton.
把握命运赠予你的机会
Take the opportunity that fate has given you.
公对公专业货运公司 警卫室
伊芙许沃 哈裡斯鑽石 在店展示中
－呼叫哈理森小姐 －你好 陌生人
- Hi, stranger. - Oh, my God!
天啊 我好想抱你
I want to hug you.
可是不行‥讨厌的病毒
I can't hug you, I can't hug you.
－送飞吻给你 －谢谢
-I'm blowing you kisses. -thank you
你好 陌生人
Hello, stranger.
－口罩要戴起来 －你不在 这裡都死气沉沉的
-Wear a mask -This place died when you left.
查萝 你一定要介绍 你的健身教练给我
Oh, Charlotte, I need to know the name of your personal trainer right now, seriously.
其实我压力大而消瘦了
I actually lost weight because of stress,
我发现我女友偷了我好多钱
'cause I found out my girlfriend was stealing a load of money from me.
－什麽？ －很复杂啦 有空再说
- What? - Long story.That's not for right now.
你好‥
Hi!
泰瑞‥
Terry, yeah.
你猜谁来了？
Terry, guess who's here?
你看１４号监视器
Yeah, have a little look at Cam 14.
呼叫哈理森小姐
Oh, shit, it's Linda.
－天啊 是琳达 －请至办公室‥
-Oh, my God. It's Linda. -Please come to the office
琳达 你怎麽会上门？
So, Linda, what are you doing here?
我不在访客名单上 我是跟伊姆兰另外有约
Oh, I'm not on the list, because I made a special arrangement with Imran,
给我一张桌子 五分锺就好
so I just need a desk for five minutes.
可以吗 查萝？
Or three minutes. Charlotte, can I?
－来吧 －好
- Come through. - Okay. Oh!
我还要等我的司机
I need to wait for my, um, driver.
等等 不好意思
Oh, hang on. Excuse me.
你好 公对公专业货运公司？
Hi. B2B Pro Freight Services?
－对 －运送伊芙许沃典藏组的？
-Yeah. -For the Eve Schwarz collection?
好 请在这边稍等一下
Yeah?Okay, just wait here for one second. Okay.
平常的货运公司叫不到了
We couldn't get our normal freight service.
－全世界都疯了 －我一定要百般盯著他
-World's gone mad. -I'm going to have to run a hundred checks on this guy.
只要他的证件就好了
We'll just need to see his ID.
伊姆兰要求我们检查司机的证件
And Imran said we do need to check the driver's ID.
当然了
Of course.
谢谢 请进
Thank you. Please come in
我可以看你的证件吗？
Yeah, can I see your ID?
谢谢
Thank you.
请到那边去签名
Please sign over there
可以了 谢谢配合
OK, thank you for your cooperation
天啊 查萝
Oh, my God, Charlotte.
我竟然会漏掉你 忘了跟你说‥
I didn't tell you. You of all people.
－怎样？ －全世界都震惊的大新闻
-What? -It's just the most earth-shattering,life-changing, amazing news.
－我有对象了‥ －不会吧
-I found someone. I met someone. - No.
－真的 －天啊 我以为你会孤独终老
- Yes. -Oh, my God. I thought you were going to be single forever.
－我也以为 －交友软件认识的吗？
- Me, too! - Dating app? Bumble?
－他人怎麽样？ －他是‥
- What's he like? - He's, uh...
他是个诗人
He's a poet.
对‥很狂野的诗人
Yeah.Yeah, he's like a really wild poet.
－天啊 太浪漫了吧 －对啊
-Oh, my God, that's so romantic. -Hmm, I know.
－我七点整要到金库取货 －对‥
But listen, I've got a slot in the vaults at 7:00.
我要带他进去办理‥谢谢
I gotta get this guy processed. Thank you.
－琳达 －人生啊人生
- Linda... - Oh, life, life.
永远不知道会有什麽惊喜
Right? You never know what's coming down the line.
好吧
Okay.
可以了
We're good.
谢谢你 马克
Thank you, Mark.
我的荣幸 琳达
Anything for you, Linda.
好了
Okay,
我给你一张通行证 你就可以自由行动
I'm going to generate you a Harrods pass that will give you access to all areas.
生日？
Date of birth.
１８０９年１月１９日
January 19th, 1809.
但一直到１８２７ 才发表第一首诗
But I didn't have my first poem published until 1827.
很好‥
Okay, that's good. That's good.
你还能开玩笑 不会惊慌
You're taking it lightly. You're not panicking.
１９８０年１月１９日
January 19th, 1980.
身高‥六尺
Height, six feet.
－体态 －精壮
- Build... - Medium athletic.
心情则很慌乱
And inside, I am panicking.
你知道我们两个都疯了吧
You do realize that we've both gone fucking insane.
他还没有犯过罪
We haven't done anything yet.
前科‥没有
Criminal convictions, none.
何时才是关键时刻？
So, when does the moment begin?
我们要决定的时刻？
The moment when we decide.
监视器控制室裡面
In the CCTV control room,
有一个会读唇语的聋人
there's a deaf man who reads lips.
闭嘴 不要乱看
Shut up. Look here.
你怎麽那麽熟练？
Why are you good at this?
Ｂ组 卸货区需要支援‥
Group B unloading area needs support
琳达
Oh, Linda.
我需要这位先生的名字
I just need to get the gentleman's name
以防火灾发生
in case of a fire, so...
他的名字？
His name?
埃德加爱伦坡
Edgar Allen Poe.
埃德加‥？
Uh, Edgar...
”埃德加爱伦坡”
Edgar Allen Poe.
好 谢谢
Great, thanks.
这是百年以来 哈洛德百货第一次关闭
This is the first time Harrods has been closed in a hundred years.
所有东西都必须装箱
Everything has to get packed up and put into boxes.
珍珠 皮包 艺术品和高级珠宝
Pearls, purses, fine art, fine jewelry.
还有鑽石
Diamonds.
没错 鑽石
Yeah. Diamonds.
电梯门要关了
The elevator door is closing
记得以前玩的游戏吗？
Remember that game we used to play
只要我们在电梯独处
when we are alone in an elevator,we ask each other questions,
就能互问问题 对方得完全如实回答
and we are only allowed to tell the absolute truth?
可恶
Shoot.
我俩之间出了什麽问题？
What went wrong with you and me?
我们初识时 我想好好疯一回
When I met you, I wanted wild and
你也很疯 然后‥
you were wild.And then,
我不想疯癫了 你也收敛了
I stopped wanting wild, and you stopped being wild.
－这样很刚好啊 －并没有
- So, it should have worked. - Yeah, but it didn't.
－为什麽？ －我不知道
- Why not? - I don't know.
这就是实话
That's the truth.
电梯门要开了
Doors opening.
你饿了吗？
Are you hungry?
饿了
Yeah.
去金库之前还有一个小时
We have an hour until our slot in the vaults,
你想吃什麽？ 这裡什麽都有
so what do you want to eat, Paxton?There is literally everything.
既然百货要关闭了 这些都会送到食物银行
With the store closing, Harrods is gonna give all of this food away to a food bank.
请各货运公司 准备好提领文件以接受检查
Please prepare the documents for inspection
我说‥
Fine.
根本没人在看
Is there anybody watching?
也许吧
Maybe.
眼光放远一点
Dream bigger.
顶级鱼子酱如何？
Finest beluga caviar?
决定时刻到了吗？
So is this the moment?
不是
No.
做决定之前 我们得先讲清楚
No. We gotta get something clear before we make up our mind.
这是意大利佩裡戈黑松露 要价７３５英镑
This is a black Perigord truffle from Italy.It retails for ￡735.
－这蘑菇太贵了吧 －好‥
- For a fucking mushroom? - Okay.
这就是我们得厘清的事
Okay, that is what we need to get clear in our minds.
对我们而言 价钱与价值有什麽差异
What is the difference between the cost of things,and the value of things to you and me?
我要准备野餐
So, I'm gonna make a picnic.
拿些平常要价五千英镑的食材
A picnic which under normal circumstances would cost us about ￡5,000.
电梯门要关了
Door's closing.
我心爱的奶奶会种族歧视
My precious grandma was a racist.
所以我脑中评判自己的 陪审团把她剔除了
And I've just decided to take her off my in-head jury of people
那这陪审团还有谁？
So, who else is on the jury?
过世的母亲 上帝 还有你
My dead mother, God and you.
－怎麽还有我？ －电梯门要开了
-How come I'm still there? -Door's opening.
门开了 我不必回答你了
Doors are open, I don't have to tell you.
我以前午休会来这裡
I used to come in here on my lunch break.
所以你想要哪一幅画？
So which one of those paintings do you want?
我不想拥有一幅画
Uh, I don't want to own one.
你想自己画一幅
You want to paint one.
我只是想画画
I just want to paint.
决定时刻到了‥
So, this is the moment.
等等
Oh, wait.
－那聋子在看吗？ －什麽？
- Is the deaf guy looking? - What?
那是我为了让你闭嘴胡诌的
Oh, I made that guy up so you would stop talking.
你想想看
Think about it.
每年十万英镑 乘以十年
￡100,000 a year for ten years.
五万英镑 乘以廿年
￡50,000 a year for 20 years.
－总共一百万英镑 －对
- A million pounds. - Yeah.
这样你就有本钱作画 根本不必卖出去
You could paint.You wouldn't even need to sell anything.
电梯门要关了
Door's closing.
我从来没学过骑单车
I never learned to ride a bicycle.
－什麽 从来没有？ －对
- What?Never?  - Yeah.
我直接学摩托车
Went straight to the motorcycle.
圣诞节前 我和玛莉滚过一次床单
Before Christmas, I had a sexual encounter with Maria,
－非常美妙 －电梯门要开了
-and it was great. -Door's opening.
好了
Okay,
目前的共识是 我们都渴望自由
so we've established that we both want freedom.
玛莉‥怎麽会？
Maria, really?
帕斯顿‥
Oh, Paxton.
我们在讨论 此生最重要的决定
Paxton, we are about to make the most important decision
拜托专心一点
of our lives. Can you concentrate?
好了
Okay,
在决策过程中 我们还没讨论过道德
in our decision-making process,we haven't yet discussed morality.
你看看 整座城市都封锁了
Look at that. That is...That's a whole city in lockdown.
医院忙不过来 一百万英镑会大有帮助
Hospitals can't cope. A million pounds would help.
这是做善事
We'd be doing good. Plus, I worked it out.
而且都是五十元钞的话 就能全装一只皮箱放门口
If it's in 50s, it all fits in one suitcase.You can leave it on a doorstep.
－去你的 奶奶 －你把她剔除陪审团了
-Take that, Grandma. - You got rid of Grandma.
没错 谢谢提醒
Yes, I did. Thank you.
好吧
So, okay,
就这麽做
we do it.
管它的 我们现在就决定
Fuck it.We decide right now.
好
Okay.
还没分手的话 我现在就会亲你
Previously, I would have kissed you.
不如试试看吧
Let's just see what happens.
－好了 －该死
- Okay. - Fuck.
－玛莉‥ －该走了
- Maria? - Okay, it's time to go.
－当真？ －要去金库那裡了
- Really? - We gotta go to the vaults.
所以我们到底要不要做？
So, are we gonna do it or not?
－你还好吗？ －糟透了
-Are you okay? -God, no.
上帝真的是 你脑中陪审团的一员？
Is God really part of your in-head jury?
没错
Uh-huh.
澄清一下 上帝对我们的行动 没有任何意见
And for the record, God is absolutely fine with whatever it is that we decide to do.
太好了
That's good to know.
－你好 你是皮杰吧？ －是的
- Hi, there. P.J., right? - Yes, miss.
－请带路吧 －这边请
-Please lead the way -Lead the way.
埃德加爱伦坡 怎麽有点耳熟？
Why does the name Edgar Allen Poe ring a bell?
拿著哈裡斯鑽石的感觉 一定很美妙
It must be wonderful to have Harris diamonds
给你 别掉了
Here you are. Don't drop it
－谢谢 －不客气
- Thank you. - You're welcome.
你要把那东西运到纽约？
You're shipping that thing to New York?
卡地亚代表请拨３５２
Representative Cartier, please dial 352
请拨３５２
Please dial 352
卡地亚代表请拨３５２
Representative Cartier, please dial 352
请拨３５２
Please dial 352
－水底世界主题 我的点子 －真不错
- It's an underwater theme. - Yeah.
你以前做得真不错
You're very good at what you do. What you did.
我们只要收拾珠宝 饰品
Okay, so we only need to pack up the jewelry and accessories.
衣服会收到楼下 所以应该不会太久
The clothing all goes downstairs,so it shouldn't take too long.
好 应该是吧
Yeah, not too long, so, uh...
我该拿出来吗？
Shall I take it out?
当然 拿吧
Yes. Why not?
－动作快 那些是食人鱼 －什麽？
-Do it quickly, the fish are piranhas. -- What?
这是个象征
It's meant to be symbolic.
－象征什麽？ －我忘了啦
- Symbolic of... - I don't remember, okay.
反正动作快一点就不会有事
Just do it faster.You'll be fine.
就是这个时刻
So, this is the moment.
原来那麽容易
Just seems so easy.
问题本来就不是能否做到 重点是‥
It's never been about can we do it, Paxton.
该不该做 要不要做 还有我们俩
It's about... should we do it?And will we do it? It's about you and me.
我们不一定会这样做 但如果真要如此
And I'm not saying that we are going to do it,but if we are,
那你就得往左踏一步
then you would need to take one step to your left.
我该踏出这一步吗？
So, shall I take the step?
先踏吧 到时候再看看
Take the step. Then, we decide.
琳达
Linda...
如果要此刻决定 我支持这麽做
if we are deciding in the moment,then I say we do it.
若要顺其自然
If we are letting the moment decide,
我认为此刻天时地利人和
then, in my opinion, the moment is saying loud and clear...
把假鑽放进箱子 真鑽放到你的包包
"Put the replica in the fucking box and put the real thing in your bag."
自由‥
Freedom,
尽在这美丽的一刻
Linda, in one beautiful moment.
－天啊 －好了‥
-god -Okay.
都在掌控之中‥
It's under control.
好 我们先处理手提包吧
Yeah.I think we should start with the handbags,
应该用防尘袋套住‥
and, uh, we should get the dust bags...
－琳达‥是我 －唐诺
- Linda, it's me. - Donald.
我有急事要找你谈
I need to speak to you urgently.
不好意思 你能到旁边散散步吗？
Um, excuse me, could you please take a stroll or something for a moment?
我有重要公事要找同事
I have some very important things to say to my colleague.
唐诺 我以为‥
Donald...Well, goodness,
我开除你了 你怎麽还在这儿
I thought that I fired you,but you're here.
琳达 听著
Linda, listen.
有匿名人士打给米拉克总公司
Someone made an anonymous call to Miracore head office.
说载运伊芙许沃珠宝的司机 用的是假名
They said that the driver from B2B who is carrying the Eve Schwarz collection
还说他有前科
They said he's got a criminal record.
奶奶 够了
Grandma, hey.
我尽快赶来了 幸好你没事
I came as soon as I could. Thank God you're okay.
－我没事 －警察要来了
- I'm okay. - Well, the police are coming.
－警察要来了‥ －随时会到
- The police are coming and... - They'll be here any minute.
随时会到？ 那要跟时间赛跑了
They'll be here any minute. Okay, that's...Now we're against the clock.
如果他没说谎 真的是清白的‥
Uh, if he's innocent and who he says he is,then everything will...
那一切就会没事 一定会的
Everything will be okay.And it will be okay,
因为我知道该怎麽做
Donald, because I know what to do.What do you mean?
什麽意思？
What are you going to do?
－帕斯顿 －帕斯顿？
- Paxton? - Paxton?
唐诺 这位是帕斯顿
Donald. Paxton.
－帕斯顿 这位是唐诺 －你是谁？
-Paxton. Donald. -Who are you?
我就是埃德加爱伦坡
I'm Edgar Allen Poe, obviously.
她明明说帕斯顿
She just called you Paxton.
他是帕斯顿
Yes, Donald, this is Paxton.
而我是个普通女人 名叫琳达贾维斯
And I'm a woman called Linda Jarvis.
我六十秒前做了一个重大决定
I'm an ordinary woman who, 60 seconds ago,made an extraordinary decision.
琳达 你要说什麽？
Linda, what are you going to tell him?
－跟他有何关系？ －有关系的地方是‥
-What is it to do with you? -What it has to do with him is that...
他是我十年以来的 合作伙伴与伴侣
he is my partner and my lover of ten years standing,
－我觉得自己还爱著他 －真的吗？
-and I think I'm still in love with him. -Really?
但最重要的是 他也是我的共犯
But most importantly, he is also my accomplice.
唐诺 就在刚刚 一分锺之前
You see, Donald, just now... just one minute ago,
我决定‥我们决定
I decided... We decided
偷走价值三百万英镑的 哈裡斯鑽石
to steal the Harris Diamond worth three million pounds.
该死 又在告解了
Holy fuck. Confession avalanche.
没事的 我认识唐诺 我们也没退路了
No, it's okay, and I know Donald
毕竟唐诺已经报警 警察随时会来
and also we don't have a choice,because Donald called the police
－如我所说 一切都会没事 －该死
-and they're about to arrive at any second. - Oh, fuck!
等警察到这裡 我们也早就离开了
it's going to be okay, because when the police arrive be here, we are going to be gone.
－是吗？ －没错
- You are? - Yes, we are.
等会儿你就告诉警察
And Donald is going to tell them
你已经和琳达聊过 她说一切安好
that he talked to Linda and she said that everything's fine,
这都只是误会
it was all a misunderstanding.
然后你再给他们这个
And then, he is going to give them this,
身份认证文件
your ID verification.
就说你在某次运送 看过那个司机
And you're going to say that you recognize that driver
接著跟他们说一个故事
from another assignment.And then, you're going to tell them a story.
说这位司机在公司有个死对头
You're going to tell them a story about how this enemy at work who hates him.
－真要我这样？ －当然
- I am? - Yes, you are.
知道你为何要照做吗 唐诺？
And do you know why you're going to do all this, Donald?
－为什麽？ －因为我们是好人
- No. Why? - Because we are good.
帕斯顿 唐诺 我们三个都是好人
Paxton, Donald, we three are good.
不管是叫我开除你的混帐 还是买鑽石的无赖
And the bastards who told me to fire you and the bastard who bought that diamond,
他们根本不会发现鑽石不见了
they won't even realize that it's gone.
－提一下健保局 －对‥
- Mention the NHS. - Yeah. Yes, ooh!
唐诺 意下如何？
What do you say, Donald?
你愿意为我们说谎吗？
Will you lie for us, Donald?
这一切混乱都是封城造成的
I see all this anarchy is because of lockdown.
封城既愚蠢又荒谬 却解放了我们所有人
Idiotic, insane fucking lockdown which has liberated us all.
我们分你钱 廿万元
Donald, we'll give you money. I'll give you 200 grand.
谁管钱 我不是为了钱 而是为了那一点美好
Fuck the money. I don't do this for money,I do this for beauty.
你们实在太棒了 琳达
Linda, you are wonderful.
你的这位秘密盗贼爱人
Linda, and he is your secret bandit lover,
两人携手反抗庞大的全球势力
and you are going to spit in the face of the global monolith.
封城期间 我有时间好好思考
During lockdown I've had time
在我妈住处旁边的公园散步
to think and walk in the park near my mother's house,
除了那些遛狗慢跑的人 到处呼吸吐气
and God, apart from the dog walkers and the joggers
老天 这世界美丽极了
breathing everywhere, God, it is a beautiful world.
就算是疫情前 我们也受限于日常琐事中
Even before the fucking virus,we were all locked down in our own routines,
－我们对自己的想像‥ －再不走就惨了
-our versions of ourselves... -Linda, we have to get the fuck out of here.
－让唐诺抒发一下 －从来不能工作
-Let Donald have his moment. -...never get to work!
我担心你 所以今晚才会来
I only came here tonight
我才不管米拉克或是臭鑽石
I don't give a fuck about Miracore,their fucking diamonds,
我才不在乎
I don't care about them.
我希望所有东西都被偷走
I want everything to be stolen.
我愿意为了你说谎 琳达
I will lie for you, Linda,
因为我这个人终于能做点什麽了
because this is my moment to fucking do something!
－还真是一团乱 －是啊
-Mad, all this, isn't it? -Yeah.
几个月前 谁想得到我们会这样？
Who'd have thought a month ago we'd be doing this.
我就料不到
Not me.
埃德加爱伦坡‥ 请至保全室
Paging Edgar Allen Poe.Edgar Allen Poe, please report to security.
埃德加爱伦坡先生 请立刻至保全室
Mr. Edgar Allen Poe,please report to security immediately.
我们得快一点
I think we should speed up.
急什麽 又不是在撤离敦克尔克
Don't rush. We're not trying to evacuate Dunkirk!
慢著 拿纸箱的话 应该要走右边
Stop there. If you walk,you should be on the starboard side.
别管了‥
Leave it. Leave it.
琳达？
Linda?
埃德加爱伦坡先生‥ 请至保全室
Paging Edgar Allen Poe.Mr. Edgar Allen Poe, please report to security.
我是麦克啊 跟你视讯过 拿箭头那个
It's Michael with the arrows from Zoom.
埃德加爱伦坡先生 请立刻至保全室
Mr. Edgar Allen Poe,please report to security immediately.
该死
Oh, fuck.
你得交出哈洛德百货的通行证
You'll have to turn in your Harrods pass.
你走吧 别管我 命运捉弄我一个人就够了
You go. Save yourself.It's me that fate is fucking with.
继续走就对了
Just keep walking.
埃德加爱伦坡
Edgar Allen Poe.
他把这个掉在办公室了
You left this in the office.
在希斯洛机场会用到
You'll need it at Heathrow.
感激不尽
Thanks very much.
琳达 大家都希望你赶快回来
Everybody says, uh, come back soon, Linda,
我们爱你
and we all love you.
欢迎莅临希斯洛机场
那晚我们讨论过 虽然我们发大财了
Since that night, we've established that although we're now both rich
也不必再做自己鄙视的工作
and no longer have to do jobs we despise,
封城造成的压力 还是大大考验了我们的感情
the strains of lockdown are still severely testing our relationship.
我们好聚好散 不要把面粉私藏起来
"Happy ever after" cannot survive someone hiding your bag of flour.
好吧 等等
Okay, come on. Okay.
你的面粉在这儿
Here is your bag of flour. I just...
答应我 你不要做面包
I want you to promise me that you're not gonna make bread.
为什麽？
Why not?
因为会一团乱 而且毫无意义
Because of the mess and the pointlessness
做好的面包也不能吃
and because it will be inedible, and like all homemade bread,
手作面包就是 毫无意义的混乱
it will be a fucking pointless cannonball.
我爸以前会做面包 我们必须吃掉
My dad used to make it and we had to eat it,
否则他会躲进工作室 用木头做可悲的玩具
otherwise he would disappear into his workshop and make these hopeless wooden toys.
－别重蹈覆辙 －琳达 你疯了
- Never again. - Linda, you've lost your mind.
什麽‥你可是埋了一只刺蝟 还在墓旁念悼词
What? I've lost...You buried a hedgehog and said a eulogy over the fucking grave.
－你还故意在天花板贴金葱 －那本来就在那裡
-And you deliberately stuck a piece of tinsel on the ceiling - above the stairs.
你差点害我脖子断了
I almost broke my fucking neck.
若你当初要我帮忙 我会拿梯子给你
If you'd asked me,I would have held the stepladders.
要是本来就在那裡 我铁定会注意到
If it had been there "all along,"I would have noticed it.
但你没注意到 整理行李根本没用
But you haven't noticed that there was no point in packing a suitcase
因为你根本没地方可去
because there is nowhere you can actually go.
政府刚延长两周的封锁
They just extended lockdown by another two weeks.
该死
Oh, shit.
大吵大闹就为了一包面粉 还有本来就有的金葱
All that for a bag of flour and a definitely pre-existing piece of tinsel.
还有‥
And
因为今天是我的生日
because today is my birthday.
－没关系‥ －我记得
-It's okay. - I know.
－我‥真的记得 －没人知道今天星期几
- It's lockdown. - No, I knew that.
－我准备了礼物 －日期就更别说了
- Nobody knows what day it is, never mind the date. - And I got you something.
这个礼物你肯定很想要
I got you something you really, really want.
尽情发挥吧
Go crazy.
－竟然还要两周 －没错
- Another two weeks? - Another two weeks.
看来又需要一首诗 抚慰受苦许久的人们
Well, then, my long suffering public may need another poem.
罗伯特格雷夫斯的”数心跳”
Counting The Beats by Robert Graves.
”爱人啊 还有我”
"You, love, and I,
”我与你”
you and I,
”若只要我与你就够了”
and if no more than only you and I,
”那我与你又在乎什麽？”
what care you and I?"
”数心跳”
"Counting the beats,
”数著缓慢心跳”
counting the slow heartbeats,
”随著缓慢心跳 流血死去”
the bleeding to death of time in slow heartbeats,
”我们清醒地躺著”
wakeful we lie.
”无云的昼夜”
Cloudless day,
”又是晴朗无云的一天”
night, and another cloudless day,
”但总有一天 一大朵云会垄罩他们的头顶”
yet a huge cloud will burst upon their heads one day."
”等那天到来 封城就会终结”
And on that day, lockdown will end!
”不是别处 就是这裡”
It's either somewhere else or here
”只在这裡 因为我们人在此处”
"Only here, as we are here, together,
”此时此刻 同在这裡”
now and here, always you and I."
”永远不变 我与你”
Never change me and you